<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>line plot on Orange</title><link>/blog/line-plot/</link><description>Recent content in line plot on Orange</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/line-plot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Mining COVID-19 Epidemics: Part 1</title><link>/blog/2020/2020-04-02-covid-19-basic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/2020-04-02-covid-19-basic/</guid><description>These days we are all following the statistics of COVID-19, looking at how our own country is faring and how it&amp;rsquo;s comparing with other countries. Luckily, only a few have a statistically meaningful number of deaths (which solemnly reminds us of the difference between statistical and practical significance!), so we concentrate on the number of confirmed cases.
You&amp;rsquo;re reading the first and most basic blog post from a series in which we will investigate this data using Orange.</description></item><item><title>Gene Expression Profiles with Line Plot</title><link>/blog/2019/6/gene-expression-profiles-with-line-plot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2019/6/gene-expression-profiles-with-line-plot/</guid><description>Line Plot is one of our recent additions to the visualization widgets. It shows data profiles, meaning it plots values for all features in the data set. Each data instance in a line plot is a line or a &amp;lsquo;profile&amp;rsquo;.
The widget can show four types of information – individual data profiles (lines), data range, mean profile and error bars. It has the same cool features of other Orange visualizations – it is interactive, meaning you can select a subset of data instances from the plot, it allows grouping by a discrete variable, and it highlights an incoming data subset.</description></item></channel></rss>