<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PCA on Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/PCA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PCA on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/PCA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Use Apply Domain</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/2021-08-13-apply-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/2021-08-13-apply-domain/</guid>
      <description>It can happen you&amp;rsquo;d see a widget in Orange and think: &amp;ldquo;What on Earth does this even do?&amp;rdquo; We admit, finding informative widget names is not always easy and Apply Domain had a least 5 different names so far. While it might not be clear what the widget does from its name, the actual functionality is one of the nicer ones Orange has to offer.
Say you are transforming your data with PCA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCA vs. MDS vs. t-SNE</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/2021-06-17-pca-mds-tsne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/2021-06-17-pca-mds-tsne/</guid>
      <description>I recently enjoy studying and showing differences between t-SNE and other data embedding and projection techniques. In particular, in some recent hands-on courses, we often introduce data visualization by principal component analysis, multidimensional scaling, and t-SNE. We would start with the zoo data set, where the data set is smaller, and the difference are less pronounced. We then traverse through employee attrition data set with exciting clusters exposed in t-SNE. To finish, and especially for the academic audience, we then show and compare the three different dimensionality reduction techniques on data from single-cell gene expression data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>