<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>clustering on Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/clustering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in clustering on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/clustering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing Clusters with a Box Plot</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/2021-10-21-cluster-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/2021-10-21-cluster-explanation/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways to cluster the data in Orange. Hiearchical clustering, k-means, and DBSCAN are just few of the widgets we can use to find groups of data instances with similar values of attributes. Once we infer the clusters, we need to analyze them to determine their characterizing features. It is there that actually the fun begins.
 Out of many ways for cluster analysis, perhaps the simplest one is by using the Box Plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Customer Segments for Business</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/2019-11-15-telekom-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/2019-11-15-telekom-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Last month we held a workshop for a large Slovenian Telco company. Their two key questions were - what machine learning techniques can we use on our data and how do we explain the models afterwards. So the workshop focused on three use cases - product segmentation, modeling churn, and clustering customers. With any kind of models, especially unsupervised ones, we often get the question - but how can we explain the clusters?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining and Machine Learning for Economists</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/07/17/data-mining-and-machine-learning-for-economists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 09:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/07/17/data-mining-and-machine-learning-for-economists/</guid>
      <description>Last week Blaž, Marko and I held a week long introductory Data Mining and Machine Learning course at the Ljubljana Doctoral Summer School 2018. We got a room full of dedicated students and we embarked on a journey through standard and advanced machine learning techniques, all presented of course in Orange. We have covered a wide array of topics, from different clustering techniques (hierarchical clustering, k-means) to predictive models (logistic regression, naive Bayes, decision trees, random forests), regression and regularization, projections, text mining and image analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girls Go Data Mining</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/06/21/girls-go-data-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 09:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/06/21/girls-go-data-mining/</guid>
      <description>This week we held our first Girls Go Data Mining workshop. The workshop brought together curious women and intuitively introduced them to essential data mining and machine learning concepts. Of course, we used Orange to explore visualizations, build predictive models, perform clustering and dive into text analysis. The workshop was supported by NumFocus through their small development grant initiative and we hope to repeat it next year with even more ladies attending!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining for Business and Public Administration</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/11/17/data-mining-business-public-administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 12:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/11/17/data-mining-business-public-administration/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been having a blast with recent Orange workshops. While Blaž was getting tanned in India, Anže and I went to the charming Liverpool to hold a session for business school professors on how to teach business with Orange.
Related: Orange in Kolkata, India
Obviously, when we say teach business, we mean how to do data mining for business, say predict churn or employee attrition, segment customers, find which items to recommend in an online store and track brand sentiment with text analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Surveys</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/10/26/analyzing-surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 11:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/10/26/analyzing-surveys/</guid>
      <description>Our streak of workshops continues. This time we taught professionals from public administration how they can leverage data analytics and machine learning to retrieve interesting information from surveys. Thanks to the Ministry of Public Administration, this is only the first in a line of workshops on data science we are preparing for public sector employees.
For this purpose, we have designed EnKlik Anketa widget, which you can find in Prototypes add-on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Voting Patterns  at AKOS Workshop</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/09/22/understanding-voting-patterns-at-akos-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 11:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/09/22/understanding-voting-patterns-at-akos-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Two days ago we held another Introduction to Data Mining workshop at our faculty. This time the target audience was a group of public sector professionals and our challenge was finding the right data set to explain key data mining concepts. Iris is fun, but not everyone is a biologist, right? Fortunately, we found this really nice data set with ballot counts from the Slovenian National Assembly (thanks to Parlameter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange at Station Houston</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/09/15/orange-at-station-houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 21:29:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/09/15/orange-at-station-houston/</guid>
      <description>With over 262 member companies, Station Houston is the largest hub for tech startups in Houston.
One of its members is also Genialis, a life science data exploration company that emerged from our lab and is now delivering pipelines and user-friendly apps for analytics in systems biology.
Thanks to the invitation by the director of operations Alex de la Fuente, we gave a seminar on Data Science for Everyone. We spoke about how Orange can support anyone to learn about data science and then use machine learning on their own data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Analytics: Clustering</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/03/image-analytics-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 12:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/03/image-analytics-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Data does not always come in a nice tabular form. It can also be a collection of text, audio recordings, video materials or even images. However, computers can only work with numbers, so for any data mining, we need to transform such unstructured data into a vector representation.
For retrieving numbers from unstructured data, Orange can use deep network embedders. We have just started to include various embedders in Orange, and for now, they are available for text and images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k-Means and Silhouette Score</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/03/17/k-means-silhouette-score/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 17:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/03/17/k-means-silhouette-score/</guid>
      <description>k-Means is one of the most popular unsupervised learning algorithms for finding interesting groups in our data. It can be useful in customer segmentation, finding gene families, determining document types, improving human resource management and so on.
But&amp;hellip; have you ever wondered how k-means works? In the following three videos we explain how to construct a data analysis workflow using k-means, how k-means works, how to find a good k value and how silhouette score can help us find the inliers and the outliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining: version 0.2.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/09/23/text-mining-version-0-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 14:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/09/23/text-mining-version-0-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Orange3-Text has just recently been polished, updated and enhanced! Our GSoC student Alexey has helped us greatly to achieve another milestone in Orange development and release the latest 0.2.0 version of our text mining add-on. The new release, which is already available on PyPi, includes Wikipedia and SimHash widgets and a rehaul of Bag of Words, Topic Modeling and Corpus Viewer.
Wikipedia widget allows retrieving sources from Wikipedia API and can handle multiple queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive k-Means</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/12/interactive-k-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 12:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/12/interactive-k-means/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest blog from the Google Summer of Code project.
As a part of my Google Summer of Code project I started developing educational widgets and assemble them in an Educational Add-On for Orange. Educational widgets can be used by students to understand how some key data mining algorithms work and by teachers to demonstrate the working of these algorithms.
Here I describe an educational widget for interactive k-means clustering, an algorithm that splits the data into clusters by finding cluster centroids such that the distance between data points and their corresponding centroid is minimized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All I See is Silhouette</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/03/23/all-i-see-is-silhouette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 09:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/03/23/all-i-see-is-silhouette/</guid>
      <description>Silhouette plot is such a nice method for visually assessing cluster quality and the degree of cluster membership that we simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to get it into Orange3. And now we did.
What this visualization displays is the average distance between instances within the cluster and instances in the nearest cluster. For a given data instance, the silhouette close to 1 indicates that the data instance is close to the center of the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Clustering: A Simple Explanation</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/12/02/hierarchical-clustering-a-simple-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 13:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/12/02/hierarchical-clustering-a-simple-explanation/</guid>
      <description>One of the key techniques of exploratory data mining is clustering – separating instances into distinct groups based on some measure of similarity. We can estimate the similarity between two data instances through euclidean (pythagorean), manhattan (sum of absolute differences between coordinates) and mahalanobis distance (distance from the mean by standard deviation), or, say, through Pearson correlation or Spearman correlation.
Our main goal when clustering data is to get groups of data instances where:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explorative data analysis with Hierarchical Clustering</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/07/20/explorative-data-analysis-with-hierarchical-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 07:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/07/20/explorative-data-analysis-with-hierarchical-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Today we will write about cluster analysis with Hierarchical Clustering widget. We use a well-known Iris data set, which contains 150 Iris flowers, each belonging to one of the three species (setosa, versicolor and virginica). To an untrained eye the three species are very alike, so how could we best tell them apart? The data set contains measurements of sepal and petal dimensions (width and length) and we assume that these gives rise to interesting clustering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn with Paint Data</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/07/10/learn-with-paint-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 07:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/07/10/learn-with-paint-data/</guid>
      <description>Paint Data widget might initially look like a kids’ game, but in combination with other Orange widgets it becomes a very simple and useful tool for conveying statistical concepts, such as k-means, hierarchical clustering and prediction models (like SVM, logistical regression, etc.).
The widget enables you to draw your data on a 2-D plane. You can name the x and y axes, select the number of classes (which are represented by different colors) and then position the points on a graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing Images</title>
      <link>/blog/2014/04/29/viewing-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 21:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014/04/29/viewing-images/</guid>
      <description>I am lately having fun with Image Viewer. The widget has been recently updated and can display images stored locally or on the internet. But wait, what images? How on earth can Orange now display images if it can handle mere tabular or basket-based data?
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example. I have considered a subset of animals from the [download id=&amp;ldquo;864&amp;rdquo;] data set (comes with Orange installation), and for demonstration purposes selected only a handful of attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
