<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Mining on Orange</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Mining on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Data Visualization</title>
      <link>/home/interactive_data_visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/interactive_data_visualization/</guid>
      <description>Orange is all about data visualizations that help to uncover hidden data patterns, provide intuition behind data analysis procedures or support communication between data scientists and domain experts. Visualization widgets include scatter plot, box plot and histogram, and model-specific visualizations like dendrogram, silhouette plot, and tree visualizations, just to mention a few. Many other visualizations are available in add-ons and include visualizations of networks, word clouds, geographical maps, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Programming</title>
      <link>/home/visual-_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/visual-_programming/</guid>
      <description>Orange is a great data mining tool for beginners as well as for expert data scientists. Thanks to its user interface users can focus on data analysis instead on laborious coding, making a construction of complex data analytics pipelines simple.
Component-Based Data Mining In Orange, data analysis is done by stacking components into workflows. Each component, called a widget, embeds some data retrieval, preprocessing, visualization, modeling or evaluation task. Combining different widgets in a workflow enables you to build comprehensive data analysis schemas as you go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teachers and Students Love It</title>
      <link>/home/teachers_and_students_love_it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/teachers_and_students_love_it/</guid>
      <description>Education in Data Science Orange is the perfect tool for hands-on training. Teachers enjoy the clear program design and the visual explorations of data and models. Students benefit from the flexibility of the tool and the power to invent new combinations of data mining methods. The educational strength of Orange comes from the combination of visual programming and interactive visualizations. We have also designed some educational widgets that have been explicitly created to support teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add-ons Extend Functionality</title>
      <link>/home/add_ons_extend_functionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/add_ons_extend_functionality/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferenc Borondics, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/home/testimonials2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/testimonials2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Francesca Vitali, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/home/testimonials3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/testimonials3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gad Shaulsky, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/home/testimonials1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/testimonials1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>