<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scripting on Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/scripting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scripting on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 09:15:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/scripting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Python Script: Managing Data on the Fly</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/05/15/python-script-managing-data-on-the-fly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 09:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/05/15/python-script-managing-data-on-the-fly/</guid>
      <description>Python Script is this mysterious widget most people don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use, even those versed in Python. Python Script is the widget that supplements Orange functionalities with (almost) everything that Python can offer. And it&amp;rsquo;s time we unveil some of its functionalities with a simple example.
Example: Batch Transform the Data There might be a time when you need to apply a function to all your attributes. Say you wish to log-transform their values, as it is common in gene expression data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining Course at Higher School of Economics, Moscow</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/05/03/data-mining-course-at-higher-school-of-economics-moscow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 11:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/05/03/data-mining-course-at-higher-school-of-economics-moscow/</guid>
      <description>Janez and I have recently returned from a two-week stay in Moscow, Russian Federation, where we were teaching data mining to MA students of Applied Statistics. This is a new Master&amp;rsquo;s course that attracts the best students from different backgrounds and teaches them statistical methods for work in the industry.
It was a real pleasure working at HSE. The students were proactive by asking questions and really challenged us to do our best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing Scraped Data</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/01/23/preparing-scraped-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 12:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/01/23/preparing-scraped-data/</guid>
      <description>One of the key questions of every data analysis is how to get the data and put it in the right form(at). In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to easily get the data from the web and transfer it to a file Orange can read.
Related: Creating a new data table in Orange through Python
First, we&amp;rsquo;ll have to do some scripting. We&amp;rsquo;ll use a couple of Python libraries - urllib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripting with Time Variable</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/06/10/scripting-with-time-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/06/10/scripting-with-time-variable/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s always fun to play around with data. And since Orange can, as of a few months ago, read temporal data, we decided to parse some data we had and put it into Orange.
TimeVariable is an extended class of continuous variable and it works with properly formated ISO standard datetime (Y-M-D h:m:s). Oftentimes our original data is not in the right format and needs to be edited first, so Orange can read it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learners in Python</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/10/16/learners-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 08:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/10/16/learners-in-python/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve already written about classifying instances in Python. However, it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to have a comprehensive list of classifiers and a step-by-step procedure at hand.
TRAINING THE CLASSIFIER
We start with simply importing Orange module into Python and loading our data set.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import Orange &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; data = Orange.data.Table(&amp;quot;titanic&amp;quot;)  We are using &amp;lsquo;titanic.tab&amp;rsquo; data. You can load any data set you want, but it does have to have a categorical class variable (for numeric targets use regression).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMLR Publishes Article on Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2013/10/03/jmlr-publishes-article-on-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 02:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013/10/03/jmlr-publishes-article-on-orange/</guid>
      <description>Journal of Machine Learning Research has just published our paper on Orange. In the paper we focus on its Python scripting part. We have last reported on Orange scripting at ECML/PKDD 2004. The manuscript was well received (over 270 citations on Google Scholar), but it is now entirely outdated. This was also our only formal publication on Orange scripting. With publication in JMLR this is now a current description of Orange and will be, for a while :-), Orange’s primary reference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
