<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Widget catalog on Orange</title>
    <link>/widget-catalog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Widget catalog on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/widget-catalog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIMA Model</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/arima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/arima/</guid>
      <description>ARIMA Model Model the time series using ARMA, ARIMA, or ARIMAX model.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget. Exogenous data: Time series of additional independent variables that can be used in an ARIMAX model.  Outputs
 Time series model: The ARIMA model fitted to input time series. Forecast: The forecast time series. Fitted values: The values that the model was actually fitted to, equals to original values - residuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AdaBoost</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/adaboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/adaboost/</guid>
      <description>AdaBoost An ensemble meta-algorithm that combines weak learners and adapts to the &amp;lsquo;hardness&amp;rsquo; of each training sample.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s) Learner: learning algorithm  Outputs
 Learner: AdaBoost learning algorithm Model: trained model  The AdaBoost (short for &amp;ldquo;Adaptive boosting&amp;rdquo;) widget is a machine-learning algorithm, formulated by Yoav Freund and Robert Schapire. It can be used with other learning algorithms to boost their performance. It does so by tweaking the weak learners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregate</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/aggregate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/aggregate/</guid>
      <description>Aggregate Aggregate data by second, minute, hour, day, week, month, or year.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  Outputs
 Time series: Aggregated time series.  Aggregate joins together instances at the same level of granularity. In other words, if aggregating by day, all instances from the same day will be merged into one. Aggregation function can be defined separately based on the type of the attribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Align Datasets</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/align_datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/align_datasets/</guid>
      <description>Align Datasets Alignment of multiple datasets with a diagram of correlation visualization.
Inputs - Data: single cell dataset
Outputs - Transformed Data: aligned data - Genes per n. Components
 Data source indicator Number of components for canonical correlation analysis. Number of shared genes and the scoring method for alignment. Scoring can be done with Pearson, Spearman and Biweights midcorrelation. Tick the box to use the percent of quantile normalization and dynamic time warping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotator</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/annotate_projection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/annotate_projection/</guid>
      <description>Annotator The widget provides an option to annotate cells with cell types based on marker genes.
Inputs - Reference Data: Data set with gene expression values. - Secondary Data: Subset of instances (optional). - Genes: Marker genes.
Outputs - Selected Data: Instances selected from the plot. - Data: Data with additional columns with annotations, clusters, and projection
This widget receives gene expression data together with mapping to a two-dimensional space and marker genes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply Domain</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/applydomain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/applydomain/</guid>
      <description>Apply Domain Given dataset and template transforms the dataset.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Template Data: template for transforming the dataset  Outputs
 Transformed Data: transformed dataset  Apply Domain maps new data into a transformed space. For example, if we transform some data with PCA and wish to observe new data in the same space, we can use Apply Domain to map the new data into the PCA space created from the original data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As Timeseries</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/as_timeseries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/as_timeseries/</guid>
      <description>../A../s../ ../T../i../m../e../s../e../r../i../e../s../ ../=../=../=../=../=../=../=../=../=../=../=../=../=../ ../ ../R../e../i../n../t../e../r../p../r../e../t../ ../a../ ../../../T../a../b../l../e../../../ ../o../b../j../e../c../t../ ../a../s../ ../a../ ../[../T../i../m../e../s../e../r../i../e../s../]../(../)../ ../o../b../j../e../c../t../&amp;hellip;/ ../ ../../../I../n../p../u../t../s../../../ ../ ../-../ ../D../a../t../a../:../ ../A../n../y../ ../d../a../t../a../ ../t../a../b../l../e../&amp;hellip;/ ../ ../../../O../u../t../p../u../t../s../../../ ../ ../-../ ../T../i../m../e../ ../s../e../r../i../e../s../:../ ../D../a../t../a../ ../t../a../b../l../e../ ../r../e../i../n../t../e../r../p../r../e../t../e../d../ ../a../s../ ../t../i../m../e../ ../s../e../r../i../e../s../&amp;hellip;/ ../ ../T../h../i../s../ ../w../i../d../g../e../t../ ../r../e../i../n../t../e../r../p../r../e../t../s../ ../a../n../y../ ../d../a../t../a../ ../t../a../b../l../e../ ../a../s../ ../a../ ../t../i../m../e../ ../s../e../r../i../e../s../,../ ../s../o../ ../i../t../ ../c../a../n../ ../b../e../ ../u../s../e../d../ ../w../i../t../h../ ../t../h../e../ ../r../e../s../t../ ../o../f../ ../t../h../e../ ../w../i../d../g../e../t../s../ ../i../n../ ../t../h../i../s../ ../a../d../d../-../o../n../&amp;hellip;/ ../I../n../ ../t../h../e../ ../w../i../d../g../e../t../,../ ../y../o../u../ ../c../a../n../ ../s../e../t../ ../w../h../i../c../h../ ../d../a../t../a../ ../a../t../t../r../i../b../u../t../e../ ../r../e../p../r../e../s../e../n../t../s../ ../t../h../e../ ../t../i../m../e../ ../v../a../r../i../a../b../l../e../&amp;hellip;/ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association Rules</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/associate/associationrules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/associate/associationrules/</guid>
      <description>Association Rules Induction of association rules.
Inputs
 Data: Data set  Outputs
 Matching Data: Data instances matching the criteria.  This widget implements FP-growth frequent pattern mining algorithm [1] with bucketing optimization [2] for conditional databases of few items. For inducing classification rules, it generates rules for the entire itemset and skips the rules where the consequent does not match one of the class&amp;rsquo; values.
 Information on the data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Average Spectra</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/average/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/average/</guid>
      <description>Average Spectra Average spectra.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Averages: averaged dataset  The Average Spectra widget enables you to calculate average spectra. It can output the average of the entire dataset, or average into groups defined by a Categorical feature.
Use Group by to output averages defined by a Categorical feature.
Columns of non-Numerical data will return a value if every row in that group has the same value, otherwise it will return Unknown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bag of Words</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/bagofwords-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/bagofwords-widget/</guid>
      <description>Bag of Words Generates a bag of words from the input corpus.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents.  Outputs
 Corpus: Corpus with bag of words features appended.  Bag of Words model creates a corpus with word counts for each data instance (document). The count can be either absolute, binary (contains or does not contain) or sublinear (logarithm of the term frequency). Bag of words model is required in combination with Word Enrichment and could be used for predictive modelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batch Effect Removal</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/batch_effect_removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/batch_effect_removal/</guid>
      <description>Batch Effect Removal Batch effect normalization on Single Cell data set.
Data - Data: Single cell dataset.
Outputs - Data: Single cell dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Box Plot</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/boxplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/boxplot/</guid>
      <description>Box Plot Shows distribution of attribute values.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected  The Box Plot widget shows the distributions of attribute values. It is a good practice to check any new data with this widget to quickly discover any anomalies, such as duplicated values (e.g. gray and grey), outliers, and alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CN2 Rule Induction</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/cn2ruleinduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/cn2ruleinduction/</guid>
      <description>CN2 Rule Induction Induce rules from data using CN2 algorithm.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: CN2 learning algorithm CN2 Rule Classifier: trained model  The CN2 algorithm is a classification technique designed for the efficient induction of simple, comprehensible rules of form &amp;ldquo;if cond then predict class&amp;rdquo;, even in domains where noise may be present.
CN2 Rule Induction works only for classification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CN2 Rule Viewer</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/cn2ruleviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/cn2ruleviewer/</guid>
      <description>CN2 Rule Viewer CN2 Rule Viewer
Inputs
 Data: dataset to filter CN2 Rule Classifier: CN2 Rule Classifier, including a list of induced rules  Outputs
 Filtered Data: data instances covered by all selected rules  A widget that displays CN2 classification rules. If data is also connected, upon rule selection, one can analyze which instances abide to the conditions.
 Original order of induced rules can be restored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSV File Import</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/csvfileimport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/csvfileimport/</guid>
      <description>CSV File Import Import a data table from a CSV formatted file.
Outputs
 Data: dataset from the .csv file Data Frame: pandas DataFrame object  The CSV File Import widget reads comma-separated files and sends the dataset to its output channel. File separators can be commas, semicolons, spaces, tabs or manually-defined delimiters. The history of most recently opened files is maintained in the widget.
Data Frame output can be used in the Python Script widget by connecting it to the in_object input (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calibrated Learner</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/calibratedlearner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/calibratedlearner/</guid>
      <description>Calibrated Learner Wraps another learner with probability calibration and decision threshold optimization.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s) Base Learner: learner to calibrate  Outputs
 Learner: calibrated learning algorithm Model: trained model using the calibrated learner  This learner produces a model that calibrates the distribution of class probabilities and optimizes decision threshold. The widget works only for binary classification tasks.
 The name under which it will appear in other widgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calibration Plot</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/evaluate/calibrationplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/evaluate/calibrationplot/</guid>
      <description>Calibration Plot Shows the match between classifiers&amp;rsquo; probability predictions and actual class probabilities.
Inputs
 Evaluation Results: results of testing classification algorithms  The Calibration Plotplots class probabilities against those predicted by the classifier(s).
 Select the desired target class from the drop down menu. Choose which classifiers to plot. The diagonal represents optimal behavior; the closer the classifier&amp;rsquo;s curve gets, the more accurate its prediction probabilities are. Thus we would use this widget to see whether a classifier is overly optimistic (gives predominantly positive results) or pessimistic (gives predominantly negative results).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choropleth Map</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/geo/choroplethmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/geo/choroplethmap/</guid>
      <description>Choropleth Map A thematic map in which areas are shaded in proportion to the measurement of the statistical variable being displayed.
Inputs - Data: An input data set.
Outputs - Selected Data: A subset of instances selected from the map. - Data: Data set with an appended meta attribute specifying selected and unselected data.
Choropleth provides an easy way to visualize how a measurement varies across a geographic area or show the level of variability within a region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cluster Analysis</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/cluster_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/cluster_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Cluster Analysis Display differentially expressed genes that characterize the cluster.
Inputs - Data: Data set. - Custom Gene Sets: Genes to compare.
Outputs - Selected Data: Data selected in the widget.
Cluster Analysis widget displays differentially expressed genes that characterize the cluster, and corresponding gene terms that describe differentially expressed genes.
 Info Cluster Indicator Batch Indicator Gene Scoring Gene Sets Custom Gene Sets Filter Genes Filter Gene Sets  Example TODO: Example</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/color/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/color/</guid>
      <description>Color Set color legend for variables.
Inputs
 Data: input data set  Outputs
 Data: data set with a new color legend  The Color widget sets the color legend for visualizations.
 A list of discrete variables. Set the color of each variable by double-clicking on it. The widget also enables renaming variables by clicking on their names. A list of continuous variables. Click on the color strip to choose a different palette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concatenate</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/concatenate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/concatenate/</guid>
      <description>Concatenate Concatenates data from multiple sources.
Inputs
 Primary Data: data set that defines the attribute set Additional Data: additional data set  Outputs
 Data: concatenated data  The widget concatenates multiple sets of instances (data sets). The merge is “vertical”, in a sense that two sets of 10 and 5 instances yield a new set of 15 instances.
 Set the attribute merging method. Add the identification of source data sets to the output data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concordance</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/concordance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/concordance/</guid>
      <description>Concordance Display the context of the word.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents.  Outputs
 Selected Documents: Documents containing the queried word. Concordances: A table of concordances.  Concordance finds the queried word in a text and displays the context in which this word is used. Results in a single color come from the same document. The widget can output selected documents for further analysis or a table of concordances for the queried word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confusion Matrix</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/evaluate/confusionmatrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/evaluate/confusionmatrix/</guid>
      <description>Confusion Matrix Shows proportions between the predicted and actual class.
Inputs
 Evaluation results: results of testing classification algorithms  Outputs
 Selected Data: data subset selected from confusion matrix Data: data with the additional information on whether a data instance was selected  The Confusion Matrix gives the number/proportion of instances between the predicted and actual class. The selection of the elements in the matrix feeds the corresponding instances into the output signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constant</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/constant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/constant/</guid>
      <description>Constant Predict the most frequent class or mean value from the training set.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: majority/mean learning algorithm Model: trained model  This learner produces a model that always predicts themajority for classification tasks and mean value for regression tasks.
For classification, when predicting the class value with Predictions, the widget will return relative frequencies of the classes in the training set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuize</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/continuize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/continuize/</guid>
      <description>Continuize Turns discrete variables (attributes) into numeric (&amp;ldquo;continuous&amp;rdquo;) dummy variables.
Inputs
 Data: input data set  Outputs
 Data: transformed data set  The Continuize widget receives a data set in the input and outputs the same data set in which the discrete variables (including binary variables) are replaced with continuous ones.
 Define the treatment of non-binary categorical variables.
Examples in this section will assume that we have a discrete attribute status with the values low, middle and high, listed in that order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/corpus-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/corpus-widget/</guid>
      <description>Corpus Load a corpus of text documents, (optionally) tagged with categories, or change the data input signal to the corpus.
Inputs
 Data: Input data (optional)  Outputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents.  Corpus widget can work in two modes: - When no data on input, it reads text corpora from files and sends a corpus instance to its output channel. History of the most recently opened files is maintained in the widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus Viewer</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/corpusviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/corpusviewer/</guid>
      <description>Corpus Viewer Displays corpus content.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents.  Outputs
 Corpus: Documents containing the queried word.  Corpus Viewer is meant for viewing text files (instances of Corpus). It will always output an instance of corpus. If RegExp filtering is used, the widget will output only matching documents.
 Information:  Documents: number of documents on the input Preprocessed: if preprocessor is used, the result is True, else False.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlations</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/correlations/</guid>
      <description>Correlations Compute all pairwise attribute correlations.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: input dataset Features: selected pair of features Correlations: data table with correlation scores  Correlations computes Pearson or Spearman correlation scores for all pairs of features in a dataset. These methods can only detect monotonic relationship.
 Correlation measure:  Pairwise Pearson correlation. Pairwise Spearman correlation.  Filter for finding attribute pairs. A list of attribute pairs with correlation coefficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlogram</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/correlogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/correlogram/</guid>
      <description>Correlogram Visualize variables&amp;rsquo; auto-correlation.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  In this widget, you can visualize the autocorrelation coefficients for the selected time series.
 Select the series to calculate autocorrelation for. See the autocorrelation coefficients. Choose to calculate the coefficients using partial autocorrelation function (PACF) instead. Choose to plot the 95% significance interval (dotted horizontal line). Coefficients that are outside of this interval might be significant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correspondence Analysis</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/correspondenceanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/correspondenceanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Correspondence Analysis Correspondence analysis for categorical multivariate data.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Coordinates: coordinates of all components  Correspondence Analysis (CA) computes the CA linear transformation of the input data. While it is similar to PCA, CA computes linear transformation on discrete rather than on continuous data.
 Select the variables you want to see plotted. Select the component for each axis. Inertia values (percentage of independence from transformation, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Class</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/createclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/createclass/</guid>
      <description>Create Class Create class attribute from a string attribute.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with a new class variable  Create Class creates a new class attribute from an existing discrete or string attribute. The widget matches the string value of the selected attribute and constructs a new user-defined value for matching instances.
 The attribute the new class is constructed from. Matching:  Name: the name of the new class value Substring: regex-defined substring that will match the values from the above-defined attribute Instances: the number of instances matching the substring Press &amp;lsquo;+&amp;rsquo; to add a new class value  Name of the new class column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DBSCAN</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/dbscan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/dbscan/</guid>
      <description>DBSCAN Groups items using the DBSCAN clustering algorithm.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with cluster index as a class attribute  The widget applies the DBSCAN clustering algorithm to the data and outputs a new dataset with cluster indices as a meta attribute. The widget also shows the sorted graph with distances to k-th nearest neighbors. With k values set to Core point neighbors as suggested in the methods article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Info</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/datainfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/datainfo/</guid>
      <description>Data Info Displays information on a selected dataset.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  A simple widget that presents information on dataset size, features, targets, meta attributes, and location.
 Information on dataset size Information on discrete and continuous features Information on targets Information on meta attributes Information on where the data is stored Produce a report.  Example Below, we compare the basic statistics of two Data Info widgets - one with information on the entire dataset and the other with information on the (manually) selected subset from the Scatter Plot widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Sampler</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/datasampler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/datasampler/</guid>
      <description>Data Sampler Selects a subset of data instances from an input dataset.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data Sample: sampled data instances Remaining Data: out-of-sample data  The Data Sampler widget implements several data sampling methods. It outputs a sampled and a complementary dataset (with instances from the input set that are not included in the sampled dataset). The output is processed after the input dataset is provided and Sample Data is pressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Table</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/datatable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/datatable/</guid>
      <description>Data Table Displays attribute-value data in a spreadsheet.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the table  The Data Table widget receives one or more datasets in its input and presents them as a spreadsheet. Data instances may be sorted by attribute values. The widget also supports manual selection of data instances.
 The name of the dataset (usually the input data file).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Databases Update</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/databases_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/databases_update/</guid>
      <description>Databases Update Updates local systems biology databases, like gene ontologies, annotations, gene names, protein interaction networks, and similar.
Inputs - None
Outputs - None
With the bioinformatics add-on you can access several databases directly from Orange. The widget can also be used to update and manage locally stored databases. To get a more detailed information on the particular database hover on its name.
 Find the desired database. A list of available databases described with data source, update availability, date of your last update and file size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/datasets/</guid>
      <description>Datasets Load a dataset from an online repository.
Outputs
 Data: output dataset  Datasets widget retrieves selected dataset from the server and sends it to the output. File is downloaded to the local memory and thus instantly available even without the internet connection. Each dataset is provided with a description and information on the data size, number of instances, number of variables, target and tags.
 Information on the number of datasets available and the number of them downloaded to the local memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difference</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/difference/</guid>
      <description>Difference Make the time series stationary by replacing it with 1st or 2nd order discrete difference along its values.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  Outputs
 Time series: Differences of input time series.   Order of differencing. Can be 1 or 2. The shift before differencing. Value of 1 equals to discrete differencing. You can use higher values to compute the difference between now and this many steps ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differential Expression</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/differential_expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/differential_expression/</guid>
      <description>Differential Expression Plots differential gene expression for selected experiments.
Inputs - Data: Data set.
Outputs - Data Subset: Differentially expressed genes. - Remaining Data Subset: Genes that were not differentially expressed. - Selected Genes: Genes from the select data with scores appended.
This widget plots a differential gene expression graph for a sample target. It takes gene expression data as an input (from dictyExpress, GEO Data Sets, etc.) and outputs a selected data subset (normally the most interesting genes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discretize</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/discretize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/discretize/</guid>
      <description>Discretize Discretizes continuous attributes from an input dataset.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with discretized values  The Discretize widget discretizes continuous attributes with a selected method.
 The basic version of the widget is rather simple. It allows choosing between three different discretizations.  Entropy-MDL, invented by Fayyad and Irani is a top-down discretization, which recursively splits the attribute at a cut maximizing information gain, until the gain is lower than the minimal description length of the cut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance File</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distancefile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distancefile/</guid>
      <description>Distance File Loads an existing distance file.
Outputs
 Distance File: distance matrix   Choose from a list of previously saved distance files. Browse for saved distance files. Reload the selected distance file. Information about the distance file (number of points, labelled/unlabelled). Browse documentation datasets. Produce a report.  Example When you want to use a custom-set distance file that you&amp;rsquo;ve saved before, open the Distance File widget and select the desired file with the Browse icon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Map</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distancemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distancemap/</guid>
      <description>Distance Map Visualizes distances between items.
Inputs
 Distances: distance matrix  Outputs
 Data: instances selected from the matrix Features: attributes selected from the matrix  The Distance Map visualizes distances between objects. The visualization is the same as if we printed out a table of numbers, except that the numbers are replaced by colored spots.
Distances are most often those between instances (&amp;rdquo;rows&amp;rdquo; in the Distances widget) or attributes (&amp;rdquo;columns&amp;rdquo; in Distances widget).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Matrix</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distancematrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distancematrix/</guid>
      <description>Distance Matrix Visualizes distance measures in a distance matrix.
Inputs
 Distances: distance matrix  Outputs
 Distances: distance matrix Table: distance measures in a distance matrix  The Distance Matrix widget creates a distance matrix, which is a two-dimensional array containing the distances, taken pairwise, between the elements of a set. The number of elements in the dataset defines the size of the matrix. Data matrices are essential for hierarchical clustering and they are extremely useful in bioinformatics as well, where they are used to represent protein structures in a coordinate-independent manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Transformation</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distancetransformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distancetransformation/</guid>
      <description>Distance Transformation Transforms distances in a dataset.
Inputs
 Distances: distance matrix  Outputs
 Distances: transformed distance matrix  The Distances Transformation widget is used for the normalization and inversion of distance matrices. The normalization of data is necessary to bring all the variables into proportion with one another.
 Choose the type of Normalization:  No normalization To interval [0, 1] To interval [-1, 1] Sigmoid function: 1/(1+exp(-X))  Choose the type of Inversion:  No inversion -X 1 - X max(X) - X 1/X  Produce a report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distances</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/distances/</guid>
      <description>Distances Computes distances between rows/columns in a dataset.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Distances: distance matrix  The Distances widget computes distances between rows or columns in a dataset. By default, the data will be normalized to ensure equal treatment of individual features. Normalization is always done column-wise.
Sparse data can only be used with Euclidean, Manhattan and Cosine metric.
The resulting distance matrix can be fed further to Hierarchical Clustering for uncovering groups in the data, to Distance Map or Distance Matrix for visualizing the distances (Distance Matrix can be quite slow for larger data sets), to MDS for mapping the data instances using the distance matrix and finally, saved with Save Distance Matrix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributions</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/distributions/</guid>
      <description>Distributions Displays value distributions for a single attribute.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  The Distributions widget displays the value distribution of discrete or continuous attributes. If the data contains a class variable, distributions may be conditioned on the class.
For discrete attributes, the graph displayed by the widget shows how many times (e.g., in how many instances) each attribute value appears in the data. If the data contains a class variable, class distributions for each of the attribute values will be displayed as well (like in the snapshot below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Map</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/docmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/docmap/</guid>
      <description>Document Map Displays geographic locations mentioned in the text.
Inputs
 Data: Data set.  Outputs
 Corpus: Documents containing mentions of selected geographical regions.  Document Map widget shows geolocations from textual (string) data. It finds mentions of geographic names (countries and capitals) and displays distributions (frequency of mentions) of these names on a map. It works with any Orange widget that outputs a data table and that contains at least one string attribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dot Matrix</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/dot_matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/dot_matrix/</guid>
      <description>Dot Matrix Perform cluster analysis.
Inputs - Data: Single cell dataset.
Outputs - Selected Data - Data: Single cell dataset. - Contingency Table</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duplicate Detection</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/duplicatedetection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/duplicatedetection/</guid>
      <description>Duplicate Detection Detect &amp;amp; remove duplicates from a corpus.
Inputs
 Distances: A distance matrix.  Outputs
 Corpus Without Duplicated: Corpus with duplicates removed. Duplicates Cluster: Documents belonging to selected cluster. Corpus: Corpus with appended cluster labels.  Duplicate Detection uses clustering to find duplicates in the corpus. It is great with the Twitter widget for removing retweets and other similar documents.
To set the level of similarity, drag the line vertical line left or right in the visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edit Domain</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/editdomain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/editdomain/</guid>
      <description>Edit Domain Rename features and their values.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with edited domain  This widget can be used to edit/change a dataset&amp;rsquo;s domain.
 All features (including meta attributes) from the input dataset are listed in the Variables list. Selecting one feature displays an editor on the right. Change the name of the feature. Change the value names for discrete features in the Values list box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EnKlik Anketa</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/educational/enklik-anketa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/educational/enklik-anketa/</guid>
      <description>EnKlik Anketa Import data from EnKlikAnketa (1ka.si) public URL.
Outputs
 Data: survey results  The EnKlik Anketa widget retrieves survey results obtained from the EnKlikAnketa service. You need to create a public link to to retrieve the results. Go to the survey you wish to retrieve, then select Data (Podatki) tab and create a public link (javna povezava) at the top right corner.
Then insert the link into the Public link URL field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Constructor</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/featureconstructor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/featureconstructor/</guid>
      <description>Feature Constructor Add new features to your dataset.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with additional features  The Feature Constructor allows you to manually add features (columns) into your dataset. The new feature can be a computation of an existing one or a combination of several (addition, subtraction, etc.). You can choose what type of feature it will be (discrete, continuous or string) and what its parameters are (name, value, expression).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Statistics</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/featurestatistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/featurestatistics/</guid>
      <description>Feature Statistics Show basic statistics for data features.
Inputs
 Data: input data  Outputs
 Reduced data: table containing only selected features Statistics: table containing statistics of the selected features  The Feature Statistics widget provides a quick way to inspect and find interesting features in a given data set.
The Feature Statistics widget on the heart-disease data set. The feature exerc ind ang was manually changed to a meta variable for illustration purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/file/</guid>
      <description>File Reads attribute-value data from an input file.
Outputs
 Data: dataset from the file  The File widget reads the input data file (data table with data instances) and sends the dataset to its output channel. The history of most recently opened files is maintained in the widget. The widget also includes a directory with sample datasets that come pre-installed with Orange.
The widget reads data from Excel (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filter</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/filter/</guid>
      <description>Filter Filter cells/genes.
Inputs - Data: input dataset
Outputs - Data: filtered dataset
The Filter widget filters cells or genes by the number of positive measurements. One can select genes in visualization to remove the unfrequent and overly frequent cells/genes.
 Information on the input and output. Filter by cells (rows), genes (columns) or data (remove zero measurments). If the box is ticked, data points are displayed. Filter by lower and upper threshold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeViz</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/freeviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/freeviz/</guid>
      <description>FreeViz Displays FreeViz projection.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data Subset: subset of instances  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected Components: FreeViz vectors  FreeViz uses a paradigm borrowed from particle physics: points in the same class attract each other, those from different class repel each other, and the resulting forces are exerted on the anchors of the attributes, that is, on unit vectors of each of the dimensional axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequent Itemsets</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/associate/frequentitemsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/associate/frequentitemsets/</guid>
      <description>Frequent Itemsets Finds frequent itemsets in the data.
Inputs
 Data: Data set  Outputs
 Matching Data: Data instances matching the criteria.  The widget finds frequent items in a data set based on a measure of support for the rule.
 Information on the data set. &amp;lsquo;Expand all&amp;rsquo; expands the frequent itemsets tree, while &amp;lsquo;Collapse all&amp;rsquo; collapses it. In Find itemsets by you can set criteria for itemset search:  Minimal support: a minimal ratio of data instances that must support (contain) the itemset for it to be generated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEO Data Sets</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/geo_data_sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/geo_data_sets/</guid>
      <description>GEO Data Sets Provides access to data sets from gene expression omnibus GEO DataSets.
Inputs - None
Outputs - Expression data: Data set selected in the widget with genes or samples in rows.
GEO DataSets is a database of gene expression curated profiles maintained by NCBI and included in the Gene Expression Omnibus. This Orange widget provides access to all its data sets and outputs a data set selected for further processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GO Browser</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/go_browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/go_browser/</guid>
      <description>GO Browser Provides access to Gene Ontology database.
Inputs - Cluster Data: Data on clustered genes. - Reference Data: Data with genes for the reference set (optional).
Outputs - Data on Selected Genes: Data on genes from the selected GO node. - Enrichment Report: Data on GO enrichment analysis.
GO Browser widget provides access to Gene Ontology database. Gene Ontology (GO) classifies genes and gene products to terms organized in a graph structure called an ontology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gene Set Enrichment</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/gene_set_enrichment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/gene_set_enrichment/</guid>
      <description>Gene Set Enrichment Enrich gene sets.
Inputs - Data: Data set. - Custom Gene Sets: Genes to compare. - Reference Genes: Genes used as reference.
Outputs - Matched Genes: Gene that match.
TODO Description.
 Info Custom Gene Set Term Column Reference Gene Sets If Commit Automatically is ticked, results will be automatically sent to the output. Alternatively, press Commit. Filtering.  Example TODO Example</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genes</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/genes/</guid>
      <description>Genes Match input gene ID&amp;rsquo;s with corresponding Entrez ID&amp;rsquo;s.
Inputs - Data: Data set.
Outputs - Data: Instances with meta data that the user has manually selected in the widget. - Genes: All genes from the input with included gene info summary and matcher result.
To work with widgets in the bioinformatics add-on data sets must be properly annotated. We need to specify: - Location of genes in a table (rows, columns) - ID from the NCBI Gene database (Entrez ID) - Organism (Taxonomy ID)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geo Map</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/geo/geomap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/geo/geomap/</guid>
      <description>Geo Map Show data points on a map.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data Subset: subset of instances  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected  Geo Map widget visualizes geo-spatial data on a map. It works on datasets containing latitude and longitude variables in WGS 84 (EPSG:4326) format. We can use it much like we use Scatter Plot widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geocoding</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/geo/geocoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/geo/geocoding/</guid>
      <description>Geocoding Encode region names into geographical coordinates, or reverse-geocode latitude and longitude pairs into regions.
Inputs - Data: An input data set.
Outputs - Coded Data: Data set with new meta attributes.
Geocoding widget extracts latitude/longitude pairs from region names or synthesizes latitude/longitude to return region name. If the region is large, say a country, encoder with return the latitude and longitude of geometric centre.
 Use region names to extract the corresponding latitude/longitude pairs:  Region identifier: attribute with the information on region names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/educational/google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/educational/google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>Google Sheets Read data from a Google Sheets spreadsheet.
Outputs
 Data: data set from the Google Sheets service.  Description The widget reads data from the Google Sheets service. To use the widget, click the Share button in a selected spreadsheet, copy the provided link and paste it into the widget&amp;rsquo;s URL line. Press enter to load the data. To observe the data in real time, use the Reload function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/educational/gradient-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/educational/gradient-descent/</guid>
      <description>Gradient Descent Educational widget that shows the gradient descent algorithm on a logistic or linear regression.
Inputs
 Data: input data set  Outputs
 Data: data with columns selected in the widget Classifier: model produced at the current step of the algorithm. Coefficients: coefficients at the current step of the algorithm.  Description This widget incrementally shows steps of gradient descent for a logistic or linear regression. Gradient descent is demonstrated on two attributes that are selected by the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granger Causality</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/granger_causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/granger_causality/</guid>
      <description>Granger Causality Test if one time series Granger-causes (i.e. can be an indicator of) another time series.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  This widgets performs a series of statistical tests to determine the series that cause other series so we can use the former to forecast the latter.
 Desired level of confidence. Maximum lag to test to. Runs the test. Denotes the minimum lag at which one series can be said to cause another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heat Map</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/heatmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/heatmap/</guid>
      <description>Heat Map Plots a heat map for a pair of attributes.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot  Heat map is a graphical method for visualizing attribute values by class in a two-way matrix. It only works on datasets containing continuous variables. The values are represented by color: the higher a certain value is, the darker the represented color. By combining class and attributes on x and y axes, we see where the attribute values are the strongest and where the weakest, thus enabling us to find typical features (discrete) or value range (continuous) for each class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Clustering</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/hierarchicalclustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/hierarchicalclustering/</guid>
      <description>Hierarchical Clustering Groups items using a hierarchical clustering algorithm.
Inputs
 Distances: distance matrix  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether an instance is selected  The widget computes hierarchical clustering of arbitrary types of objects from a matrix of distances and shows a corresponding dendrogram.
 The widget supports four ways of measuring distances between clusters:  Single linkage computes the distance between the closest elements of the two clusters Average linkage computes the average distance between elements of the two clusters Weighted linkage uses the WPGMA method Complete linkage computes the distance between the clusters&amp;rsquo; most distant elements  Labels of nodes in the dendrogram can be chosen in the Annotation box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyperSpectra</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/hyperspectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/hyperspectra/</guid>
      <description>HyperSpectra Plots 2D map of hyperspectra.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Selection: spectra from selected area Data: dataset with information whether a spectrum was selected or not  The HyperSpectra widget plots hyperspectra that were read from the .map file. To use this widget with infrared spectral data, you need to transform it with Reshape Map widget.
At the top, HyperSpectra shows a 2D map of a slice of the spectra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Embedding</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/imageembedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/imageembedding/</guid>
      <description>Image Embedding Image embedding through deep neural networks.
Inputs
 Images: List of images.  Outputs
 Embeddings: Images represented with a vector of numbers. Skipped Images: List of images where embeddings were not calculated.  Image Embedding reads images and uploads them to a remote server or evaluate them locally. Deep learning models are used to calculate a feature vector for each image. It returns an enhanced data table with additional columns (image descriptors).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Grid</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/imagegrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/imagegrid/</guid>
      <description>Image Grid Displays images in a similarity grid.
Inputs
 Embeddings: Image embeddings from Image Embedding widget. Data Subset: A subset of embeddings or images.  Outputs
 Images: Images from the dataset with an additional column specifying if the image is selected or the group, if there are several. Selected Images: Selected images with an additional column specifying the group.  The Image Grid widget can display images from a dataset in a similarity grid - images with similar content are placed closer to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Viewer</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/imageviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/imageviewer/</guid>
      <description>Image Viewer Displays images that come with a data set.
Inputs
 Data: A data set with images.  Outputs
 Data: Images that come with the data. Selected images: Images selected in the widget.  The Image Viewer widget can display images from a data set, which are stored locally or on the internet. The widget will look for an attribute with type=image in the third header row. It can be used for image comparison, while looking for similarities or discrepancies between selected data instances (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Documents</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/importdocuments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/importdocuments/</guid>
      <description>Import Documents Import text documents from folders.
Inputs
 None  Outputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents from the local machine.  Import Documents widget retrieves text files from folders and creates a corpus. The widget reads .txt, .docx, .odt, .pdf and .xml files. If a folder contains subfolders, they will be used as class labels.
 Folder being loaded. Load folder from a local machine. Reload the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Images</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/importimages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/importimages/</guid>
      <description>Import Images Import images from a directory(s).
Outputs
 Data: Dataset describing one image in each row.  Import Images walks through a directory and returs one row per located image. Columns include image name, path to image, width, height and image size. Column with image path is later used as an attribute for image visualization and embedding.
 Currently loaded folder. Select the folder to load. Click Reload to update imported images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impute</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/impute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/impute/</guid>
      <description>Impute Replaces unknown values in the data.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Learner: learning algorithm for imputation  Outputs
 Data: dataset with imputed values  Some Orange&amp;rsquo;s algorithms and visualizations cannot handle unknown values in the data. This widget does what statisticians call imputation: it substitutes missing values by values either computed from the data or set by the user. The default imputation is (1-NN).
 In the top-most box, Default method, the user can specify a general imputation technique for all attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrate Spectra</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/integrate-spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/integrate-spectra/</guid>
      <description>Integrate Spectra Integrate spectra in various ways.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Integrated Data: data with integrals appended Preprocessor: preprocessing method  The Integrate Spectra widget allows you to add integrals to your data by selecting regions of interest and integrating them with several methods.
 Add integral:  Integral from 0: Integral from baseline: Peak from 0: Peak from baseline: Closest value: X-value of maximum from 0: X-value of maximum from baseline  Toggle preview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive k-Means</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/educational/interactive-kmeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/educational/interactive-kmeans/</guid>
      <description>Interactive k-Means Educational widget that shows the working of a k-means clustering.
Inputs
 Data: input data set  Outputs
 Data: data set with cluster annotation Centroids: centroids position  Description The aim of this widget is to show the working of a k-means clustering algorithm on two attributes from a data set. The widget applies k-means clustering to the selected two attributes step by step. Users can step through the algorithm and see how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferogram to Spectrum</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/interferogram-to-spectrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/interferogram-to-spectrum/</guid>
      <description> Interferogram to Spectrum Performs Fast Fourier Transform on an interferogram, including zero filling, apodization and phase correction.
Inputs
 Interferogram: input interferogram  Outputs
 Spectra: dataset with spectra Phases: phases  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpolate</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/interpolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/interpolate/</guid>
      <description>Interpolate Interpolate spectra.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Points: a reference data set  Outputs
 Interpolated Data: aligned dataset  The Interpolate widget enables you to align datasets with different wavenumbers. It has automatic interpolation or you can provide the reference data set to align with.
 Enable automatic interpolation: creates a new domain, which consequently enables interpolation of values on test data. Linear interval:  Min: minimum cutoff Max: maximum cutoff Delta: the difference between the cutoffs  Reference data: the data is aligned to the reference data  Examples The first example shows how to use Interpolate to align the train and test data set of spectral data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpolate</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/interpolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/interpolate/</guid>
      <description>Interpolate Induce missing values in the time series by interpolation.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  Outputs
 Time series: The input time series with the chosen default interpolation method for when the algorithms require interpolated time series (without missing values). Interpolated time series: The input time series with any missing values interpolated according to the chosen interpolation method.  Most time series algorithms assume, you don&amp;rsquo;t have any missing values in your data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KEGG Pathways</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/kegg_pathways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/kegg_pathways/</guid>
      <description>KEGG Pathways Diagrams of molecular interactions, reactions, and relations.
Inputs - Data: Data set. - Reference: Referential data set.
Outputs - Selected Data: Data subset. - Unselected Data: Remaining data.
KEGG Pathways widget displays diagrams of molecular interactions, reactions and relations from the KEGG Pathways Database. It takes data on gene expression as an input, matches the genes to the biological processes and displays a list of corresponding pathways. To explore the pathway, the user can click on any process from the list or arrange them by P-value to get the most relevant processes at the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lift Curve</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/evaluate/liftcurve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/evaluate/liftcurve/</guid>
      <description>Lift Curve Measures the performance of a chosen classifier against a random classifier.
Inputs
 Evaluation Results: results of testing classification algorithms  The Lift curve shows the relation between the number of instances which were predicted positive and those that are indeed positive and thus measures the performance of a chosen classifier against a random classifier. The graph is constructed with the cumulative number of cases (in descending order of probability) on the x-axis and the cumulative number of true positives on the y-axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line Chart</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/line_chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/line_chart/</guid>
      <description>Line Chart Visualize time series&amp;rsquo; sequence and progression in the most basic time series visualization imaginable.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget. Forecast: Time series forecast as output by one of the models (like VAR or ARIMA).  You can visualize the time series in this widget.
 Stack a new line chart below the current charts. Remove the associated stacked chart. Type of chart to draw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line Plot</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/lineplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/lineplot/</guid>
      <description>Line Plot Visualization of data profiles (e.g., time series).
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data Subset: subset of instances  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected  Line plot a type of plot which displays the data as a series of points, connected by straight line segments. It only works for numerical data, while categorical can be used for grouping of the data points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Projection</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/linearprojection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/linearprojection/</guid>
      <description>Linear Projection A linear projection method with explorative data analysis.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data Subset: subset of instances Projection: custom projection vectors  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected Components: projection vectors  This widget displays linear projections of class-labeled data. It supports various types of projections such as circular, linear discriminant analysis, principal component analysis, and custom projection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Regression</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/linearregression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/linearregression/</guid>
      <description>Linear Regression A linear regression algorithm with optional L1 (LASSO), L2 (ridge) or L1L2 (elastic net) regularization.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: linear regression learning algorithm Model: trained model Coefficients: linear regression coefficients  The Linear Regression widget constructs a learner/predictor that learns a linear function from its input data. The model can identify the relationship between a predictor xi and the response variable y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Data</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/load_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/load_data/</guid>
      <description>Load Data Load samples for multi-sample analysis.
Outputs - Data: Single cell dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Model</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/loadmodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/loadmodel/</guid>
      <description>Load Model Load a model from an input file.
Outputs
 Model: trained model   Choose from a list of previously used models. Browse for saved models. Reload the selected model.  Example When you want to use a custom-set model that you&amp;rsquo;ve saved before, open the Load Model widget and select the desired file with the Browse icon. This widget loads the existing model into Predictions widget. Datasets used with Load Model have to contain compatible attributes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/logisticregression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/logisticregression/</guid>
      <description>Logistic Regression The logistic regression classification algorithm with LASSO (L1) or ridge (L2) regularization.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: logistic regression learning algorithm Model: trained model Coefficients: logistic regression coefficients  Logistic Regression learns a Logistic Regression model from the data. It only works for classification tasks.
 A name under which the learner appears in other widgets. The default name is &amp;ldquo;Logistic Regression&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louvain Clustering</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/louvainclustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/louvainclustering/</guid>
      <description>Louvain Clustering Groups items using the Louvain clustering algorithm.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with cluster index as a class attribute Graph (with the Network addon): the weighted k-nearest neighbor graph  The widget first converts the input data into a k-nearest neighbor graph. To preserve the notions of distance, the Jaccard index for the number of shared neighbors is used to weight the edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MDS</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/mds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/mds/</guid>
      <description>MDS Multidimensional scaling (MDS) projects items onto a plane fitted to given distances between points.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Distances: distance matrix Data Subset: subset of instances  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: dataset with MDS coordinates  Multidimensional scaling is a technique which finds a low-dimensional (in our case a two-dimensional) projection of points, where it tries to fit distances between points as well as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifold Learning</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/manifoldlearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/manifoldlearning/</guid>
      <description>Manifold Learning Nonlinear dimensionality reduction.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Transformed Data: dataset with reduced coordinates  Manifold Learning is a technique which finds a non-linear manifold within the higher-dimensional space. The widget then outputs new coordinates which correspond to a two-dimensional space. Such data can be later visualized with Scatter Plot or other visualization widgets.
 Method for manifold learning:  t-SNE MDS, see also MDS widget Isomap Locally Linear Embedding Spectral Embedding  Set parameters for the method:  t-SNE (distance measures):  Euclidean distance Manhattan Chebyshev Jaccard Mahalanobis Cosine  MDS (iterations and initialization):  max iterations: maximum number of optimization interactions initialization: method for initialization of the algorithm (PCA or random)  Isomap:  number of neighbors  Locally Linear Embedding:  method: standard modified hessian eigenmap local number of neighbors max iterations  Spectral Embedding:  affinity: nearest neighbors RFB kernel   Output: the number of reduced features (components).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marker Genes</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/marker_genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/marker_genes/</guid>
      <description>Marker Genes Widget provides access to a public database of marker genes.
Outputs - Genes
Database sources:
 PanglaoDB
Oscar Franzén, Li-Ming Gan, Johan L M Björkegren, PanglaoDB: a web server for exploration of mouse and human single-cell RNA sequencing data, Database, Volume 2019, 2019, baz046, https://doi.org/10.1093/database/baz046
  
 CellMarker
CellMarker: a manually curated resource of cell markers in human and mouse. Nucleic Acids Research. 2018.
  Data is preprocessed in Orange readable format and it is hosted here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merge Data</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/mergedata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/mergedata/</guid>
      <description>Merge Data Merges two datasets, based on values of selected attributes.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Extra Data: additional dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with features added from extra data  The Merge Data widget is used to horizontally merge two datasets, based on the values of selected attributes (columns). In the input, two datasets are required, data and extra data. Rows from the two data sets are matched by the values of pairs of attributes, chosen by the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Evaluation</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/model_evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/model_evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Model Evaluation Evaluate different time series&amp;rsquo; models.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget. Time series model(s): The time series model(s) to evaluate (e.g. VAR or ARIMA).  Evaluate different time series&amp;rsquo; models. by comparing the errors they make in terms of: root mean squared error (RMSE), median absolute error (MAE), mean absolute percent error (MAPE), prediction of change in direction (POCID), coefficient of determination (R²), Akaike information criterion (AIC), and Bayesian information criterion (BIC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosaic Display</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/mosaicdisplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/mosaicdisplay/</guid>
      <description>Mosaic Display Display data in a mosaic plot.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data subset: subset of instances  Outputs
 Selected data: instances selected from the plot  The Mosaic plot is a graphical representation of a two-way frequency table or a contingency table. It is used for visualizing data from two or more qualitative variables and was introduced in 1981 by Hartigan and Kleiner and expanded and refined by Friendly in 1994.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Transform</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/moving_transform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/moving_transform/</guid>
      <description>Moving Transform Apply rolling window functions to the time series. Use this widget to get a series&amp;rsquo; mean.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  Outputs
 Time series: The input time series with the added series&amp;rsquo; transformations.  In this widget, you define what aggregation functions to run over the time series and with what window sizes.
 Define a new transformation. Remove the selected transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multifile</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/multifile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/multifile/</guid>
      <description>Multifile Read data from input files and send a data table to the output.
Outputs
 Data: a data table of all the loaded files  The Multifile widget loads data from different sources and works like Concatenate widget for spectroscopy. The widget will output a union of attributes and features, with missing values for non-matching wavenumbers. To interpolate missing data, use the Interpolate widget.
 Loaded files. Load local files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NY Times</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/nytimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/nytimes/</guid>
      <description>NY Times Loads data from the New York Times&amp;rsquo; Article Search API.
Inputs
 None  Outputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents from the New York Times newspaper.  NYTimes widget loads data from New York Times&amp;rsquo; Article Search API. You can query NYTimes articles from September 18, 1851 to today, but the API limit is set to allow retrieving only a 1000 documents per query. Define which features to use for text mining, Headline and Abstract being selected by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naive Bayes</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/naivebayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/naivebayes/</guid>
      <description>Naive Bayes A fast and simple probabilistic classifier based on Bayes&amp;rsquo; theorem with the assumption of feature independence.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: naive bayes learning algorithm Model: trained model  Naive Bayes learns a Naive Bayesian model from the data. It only works for classification tasks.
This widget has two options: the name under which it will appear in other widgets and producing a report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighbors</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/neighbors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/neighbors/</guid>
      <description>Neighbors Compute nearest neighbors in data according to reference.
Inputs
 Data: An input data set. Reference: A reference data for neighbor computation.  Outputs
 Neighbors: A data table of nearest neighbors according to reference.  The Neighbors widget computes nearest neighbors for a given reference and for a given distance measure. The reference can be either one instance or more instances. In the case with one reference widget outputs closest n instances from data where n is set by the Number of neighbors option in the widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Analysis</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/networks/networkanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/networks/networkanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Network Analysis Statistical analysis of network data.
Inputs
 Network: An instance of Network Graph. Items: Properties of a network file.  Outputs
 Network: An instance of Network Graph with appended information. Items: New properties of a network file.  Network Analysis widget computes node-level and graph-level summary statistics for the network. It outputs a network with the new computed statistics and an extended item data table (node-level indices only).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Clustering</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/networks/networkclustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/networks/networkclustering/</guid>
      <description>Network Clustering Detect clusters in a network.
Inputs
 Network: An instance of Network Graph.  Outputs
 Network: An instance of Network Graph with clustering information appended.  Network Clustering widget finds clusters in a network. Clustering works with two algorithms, one from Raghavan et al. (2007), which uses label propagation to find appropriate clusters, and one from Leung et al. (2009), which builds upon the work from Raghavan and adds hop attenuation as a parameters for cluster formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Explorer</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/networks/networkexplorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/networks/networkexplorer/</guid>
      <description>Network Explorer Visually explore the network and its properties.
Inputs
 Network: An instance of Network Graph. Node Subset: A subset of vertices. Node Data: Information on vertices. Node Distances: Data on distances between nodes.  Outputs
 Selected sub-network: A network of selected nodes. Distance Matrix: Distance matrix. Selected Items: Information on selected vertices. Highlighted Items: Information on highlighted vertices. Remaining Items: Information on remaining items (not selected or highlighted).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network File</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/networks/networkfile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/networks/networkfile/</guid>
      <description>Network File Read network graph file in Pajek format.
Outputs
 Network: An instance of Network Graph. Items: Properties of a network file.  Network File widget reads network files and sends the input data to its output channel. History of the most recently opened files in maintained in the widget. The widget also includes a directory with sample data sets that come pre-installed with the add-on.
The widget reads data in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network From Distances</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/networks/networkfromdistances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/networks/networkfromdistances/</guid>
      <description>Network From Distances Constructs a network from distances between instances.
Inputs
 Distances: A distance matrix.  Outputs
 Network: An instance of Network Graph. Data: Attribute-valued data set. Distances: A distance matrix.  Network from Distances constructs a network graph from a given distance matrix. Graph is constructed by connecting nodes from the matrix where the distance between nodes is below the given threshold. In other words, all instances with a distance lower than the selected threshold, will be connected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Generator</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/networks/networkgenerator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/networks/networkgenerator/</guid>
      <description>Network Generator Construct example graphs.
Outputs
 Generated Network: An instance of Network Graph.  Network Generator constructs exemplary networks. It is mostly intended for teaching/learning about networks.
Graph options:
 Path: a graph that can be drawn so that all of its vertices and edges lie on a single straight line. Cycle: a graph that consists of a single cycle, i.e. some number of vertices (at least 3) are connected in a closed chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Of Groups</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/networks/networkofgroups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/networks/networkofgroups/</guid>
      <description>Network Of Groups Group instances by feature and connect related groups.
Inputs
 Network: An instance of network graph. Data: Properties of a network graph.  Outputs:
 Network: A grouped network graph. Data: Properties of the group network graph.  Network of Groups is the network version of the group-by operation. Nodes with the same values of the attribute, selected in the dropdown, will be represented as a single node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/neuralnetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/neuralnetwork/</guid>
      <description>Neural Network A multi-layer perceptron (MLP) algorithm with backpropagation.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: multi-layer perceptron learning algorithm Model: trained model  The Neural Network widget uses sklearn&amp;rsquo;s Multi-layer Perceptron algorithm that can learn non-linear models as well as linear.
 A name under which it will appear in other widgets. The default name is &amp;ldquo;Neural Network&amp;rdquo;. Set model parameters:  Neurons per hidden layer: defined as the ith element represents the number of neurons in the ith hidden layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nomogram</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/nomogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/nomogram/</guid>
      <description>Nomogram Nomograms for visualization of Naive Bayes and Logistic Regression classifiers.
Inputs
 Classifier: trained classifier Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Features: selected variables, 10 by default  The Nomogram enables some classifier&amp;rsquo;s (more precisely Naive Bayes classifier and Logistic Regression classifier) visual representation. It offers an insight into the structure of the training data and effects of the attributes on the class probabilities. Besides visualization of the classifier, the widget offers interactive support for prediction of class probabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/outliers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/outliers/</guid>
      <description>Outliers Simple outlier detection by comparing distances between instances.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Distances: distance matrix  Outputs
 Outliers: instances scored as outliers Inliers: instances not scored as outliers  The Outliers widget applies one of the two methods for outlier detection. Both methods apply classification to the dataset, one with SVM (multiple kernels) and the other with elliptical envelope. One-class SVM with non-linear kernels (RBF) performs well with non-Gaussian distributions, while Covariance estimator works only for data with Gaussian distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCA</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/pca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/pca/</guid>
      <description>PCA PCA linear transformation of input data.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Transformed Data: PCA transformed data Components: Eigenvectors.  Principal Component Analysis (PCA) computes the PCA linear transformation of the input data. It outputs either a transformed dataset with weights of individual instances or weights of principal components.
 Select how many principal components you wish in your output. It is best to choose as few as possible with variance covered as high as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paint Data</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/paintdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/paintdata/</guid>
      <description>Paint Data Paints data on a 2D plane. You can place individual data points or use a brush to paint larger datasets.
Outputs
 Data: dataset as painted in the plot  The widget supports the creation of a new dataset by visually placing data points on a two-dimension plane. Data points can be placed on the plane individually (Put) or in a larger number by brushing (Brush). Data points can belong to classes if the data is intended to be used in supervised learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Periodogram</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/periodogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/periodogram/</guid>
      <description>Periodogram Visualize time series&amp;rsquo; cycles, seasonality, periodicity, and most significant periods.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  In this widget, you can visualize the most significant periods of the time series.
 Select the series to calculate the periodogram for. See the periods and their respective relative power spectral density estimates.  Periodogram for non-equispaced series is calculated using Lomb-Scargle method.
See also Correlogram</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pie Chart</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/educational/pie-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/educational/pie-chart/</guid>
      <description>Pie Chart The widget for visualizing discrete attributes in the pie chart.
Inputs
 Data: input data set  The aim of this widget is to demonstrate that pie charts are a terrible visualization. Please don&amp;rsquo;t use it for any other purpose.
 Select the attribute you want to visualize. Select the attribute which is used to split data in more charts. Check if you want pies to be exploded (parts of the pie will have space in between).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pivot Table</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/pivot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/pivot/</guid>
      <description>Pivot Table Reshape data table based on column values.
Inputs
 Data: input data set  Outputs
 Pivot Table: contingency matrix as shown in the widget Filtered Data: subset selected from the plot Grouped Data: aggregates over groups defined by row values  Pivot Table summarizes the data of a more extensive table into a table of statistics. The statistics can include sums, averages, counts, etc. The widget also allows selecting a subset from the table and grouping by row values, which have to be a discrete variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polynomial Classification</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/educational/polynomial-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/educational/polynomial-classification/</guid>
      <description>Polynomial Classification Educational widget that visually demonstrates classification in two classes for any classifier.
Inputs
 Data: input data set Preprocessor: data preprocessors Learner: classification algorithm used in the widget. Default set to Logistic Regression Learner.  Outputs
 Learner: classification algorithm used in the widget Classifier: trained classifier Coefficients: classifier coefficients if it has them  Description This widget interactively shows classification probabilities for classification in two classes using color gradient and contour lines for any classifiers from the Model section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polynomial Regression</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/educational/polynomial-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/educational/polynomial-regression/</guid>
      <description>Polynomial Regression Educational widget that interactively shows regression line for different regressors.
Inputs
 Data: input data set. It needs at least two continuous attributes. Preprocessor: data preprocessors Learner: regression algorithm used in the widget. Default set to Linear Regression.  Outputs
 Learner: regression algorithm used in the widget Predictor: trained regressor Coefficients: regressor coefficients if any  Description This widget interactively shows the regression line using any of the regressors from the Model module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictions</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/evaluate/predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/evaluate/predictions/</guid>
      <description>Predictions Shows models&amp;rsquo; predictions on the data.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Predictors: predictors to be used on the data  Outputs
 Predictions: data with added predictions Evaluation Results: results of testing classification algorithms  The widget receives a dataset and one or more predictors (predictive models, not learning algorithms - see the example below). It outputs the data and the predictions.
 Information on the input, namely the number of instances to predict, the number of predictors and the task (classification or regression).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preprocess</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/preprocess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/preprocess/</guid>
      <description>Preprocess Preprocesses data with selected methods.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Preprocessor: preprocessing method Preprocessed Data: data preprocessed with selected methods  Preprocessing is crucial for achieving better-quality analysis results. The Preprocess widget offers several preprocessing methods that can be combined in a single preprocessing pipeline. Some methods are available as separate widgets, which offer advanced techniques and greater parameter tuning.
 List of preprocessors. Double click the preprocessors you wish to use and shuffle their order by dragging them up or down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preprocess Spectra</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/preprocess-spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/preprocess-spectra/</guid>
      <description>Preprocess Spectra Construct a data preprocessing pipeline.
Inputs
 Data: input data set Reference: a reference data set used in some preprocessing methods  Outputs
 Preprocessed Data: transformed data set Preprocessor: preprocessing methods  The Preprocess Spectra widget applied several preprocessing methods to spectral data. You select the preprocessing method from the list and press the triangle button on the right to apply it. The order of the preprocessing matters, so to change the order of the preprocessing, just drag and drop the method to its proper place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preprocess Text</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/preprocesstext/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/preprocesstext/</guid>
      <description>Preprocess Text Preprocesses corpus with selected methods.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents.  Outputs
 Corpus: Preprocessed corpus.  Preprocess Text splits your text into smaller units (tokens), filters them, runs normalization (stemming, lemmatization), creates n-grams and tags tokens with part-of-speech labels. Steps in the analysis are applied sequentially and can be turned on or off.
 Information on preprocessed data. Document count reports on the number of documents on the input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pubmed</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/pubmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/pubmed/</guid>
      <description>Pubmed Fetch data from PubMed journals.
Inputs
 None  Outputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents from the PubMed online service.  PubMed comprises more than 26 million citations for biomedical literature from MEDLINE, life science journals, and online books. The widget allows you to query and retrieve these entries. You can use regular search or construct advanced queries.
 Enter a valid e-mail to retrieve queries. Regular search:  Author: queries entries from a specific author.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purge Domain</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/purgedomain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/purgedomain/</guid>
      <description>Purge Domain Removes unused attribute values and useless attributes, sorts the remaining values.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: filtered dataset  Definitions of nominal attributes sometimes contain values which don’t appear in the data. Even if this does not happen in the original data, filtering the data, selecting exemplary subsets and alike can remove all examples for which the attribute has some particular value. Such values clutter data presentation, especially various visualizations, and should be removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagorean Forest</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/pythagoreanforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/pythagoreanforest/</guid>
      <description>Pythagorean Forest Pythagorean forest for visualizing random forests.
Inputs
 Random Forest: tree models from random forest  Outputs
 Tree: selected tree model  Pythagorean Forest shows all learned decision tree models from Random Forest widget. It displays them as Pythagorean trees, each visualization pertaining to one randomly constructed tree. In the visualization, you can select a tree and display it in Pythagorean Tree widget. The best tree is the one with the shortest and most strongly colored branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagorean Tree</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/pythagoreantree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/pythagoreantree/</guid>
      <description>Pythagorean Tree Pythagorean tree visualization for classification or regression trees.
Inputs
 Tree: tree model Selected Data: instances selected from the tree  Pythagorean Trees are plane fractals that can be used to depict general tree hierarchies as presented in an article by Fabian Beck and co-authors. In our case, they are used for visualizing and exploring tree models, such as Tree.
 Information on the input tree model. Visualization parameters:  Depth: set the depth of displayed trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Script</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/pythonscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/pythonscript/</guid>
      <description>Python Script Extends functionalities through Python scripting.
Inputs
 Data (Orange.data.Table): input dataset bound to in_data variable Learner (Orange.classification.Learner): input learner bound to in_learner variable Classifier (Orange.classification.Learner): input classifier bound to in_classifier variable Object: input Python object bound to in_object variable  Outputs
 Data (Orange.data.Table): dataset retrieved from out_data variable Learner (Orange.classification.Learner): learner retrieved from out_learner variable Classifier (Orange.classification.Learner): classifier retrieved from out_classifier variable Object: Python object retrieved from out_object variable  Python Script widget can be used to run a python script in the input, when a suitable functionality is not implemented in an existing widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROC Analysis</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/evaluate/rocanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/evaluate/rocanalysis/</guid>
      <description>ROC Analysis Plots a true positive rate against a false positive rate of a test.
Inputs
 Evaluation Results: results of testing classification algorithms  The widget shows ROC curves for the tested models and the corresponding convex hull. It serves as a mean of comparison between classification models. The curve plots a false positive rate on an x-axis (1-specificity; probability that target=1 when true value=0) against a true positive rate on a y-axis (sensitivity; probability that target=1 when true value=1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radviz</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/radviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/radviz/</guid>
      <description>Radviz Radviz vizualization with explorative data analysis and intelligent data visualization enhancements.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data Subset: subset of instances  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected Components: Radviz vectors  Radviz (Hoffman et al. 1997) is a non-linear multi-dimensional visualization technique that can display data defined by three or more variables in a 2-dimensional projection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Data</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/educational/random-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/educational/random-data/</guid>
      <description>Random Data Generate random data sample.
Inputs
 None  Outputs
 Data: randomly generated data  Random Data allows creating random data sets, where variables correspond to the selected distributions. The user can specify the number of rows (samples) and the number of variables for each distribution. Distributions from the Scipy&amp;rsquo;s stats module are used.
 Normal: A normal continuous random variable. Set the number of variables, the mean and the variance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Forest</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/randomforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/randomforest/</guid>
      <description>Random Forest Predict using an ensemble of decision trees.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: random forest learning algorithm Model: trained model  Random forest is an ensemble learning method used for classification, regression and other tasks. It was first proposed by Tin Kam Ho and further developed by Leo Breiman (Breiman, 2001) and Adele Cutler.
Random Forest builds a set of decision trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomize</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/randomize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/randomize/</guid>
      <description>Randomize Shuffles classes, attributes and/or metas of an input dataset.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: randomized dataset  The Randomize widget receives a dataset in the input and outputs the same dataset in which the classes, attributes or/and metas are shuffled.
 Select group of columns of the dataset you want to shuffle. Select proportion of the dataset you want to shuffle. Produce replicable output. If Apply automatically is ticked, changes are committed automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rank</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/rank/</guid>
      <description>Rank Ranking of attributes in classification or regression datasets.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Scorer: models for feature scoring  Outputs
 Reduced Data: dataset with selected attributes  The Rank widget considers class-labeled datasets (classification or regression) and scores the attributes according to their correlation with the class. Rank accepts also models for scoring, such as linear regression, logistic regression, random forest, SGD, etc.
 Select attributes from the data table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reshape Map</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/reshape-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/reshape-map/</guid>
      <description> Reshape Map Builds or modifies the shape of the input dataset to create 2D maps from series data or change the dimensions of existing 2D datasets.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Map Data: data as a map  The Reshape Map widget transforms the input data to a map.
 Map shape:  The X dimension. The Y dimension.  Send data automatically or press Send.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Table</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/sqltable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/sqltable/</guid>
      <description>SQL Table Reads data from an SQL database.
Outputs
 Data: dataset from the database  The SQL widget accesses data stored in an SQL database. It can connect to PostgreSQL (requires psycopg2 module) or SQL Server (requires pymssql module).
To handle large databases, Orange attempts to execute a part of the computation in the database itself without downloading the data. This only works with PostgreSQL database and requires quantile and tsm_system_time extensions installed on server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVM</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/svm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/svm/</guid>
      <description>SVM Support Vector Machines map inputs to higher-dimensional feature spaces.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: linear regression learning algorithm Model: trained model Support Vectors: instances used as support vectors  Support vector machine (SVM) is a machine learning technique that separates the attribute space with a hyperplane, thus maximizing the margin between the instances of different classes or class values. The technique often yields supreme predictive performance results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Data</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/save/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/save/</guid>
      <description>Save Data Saves data to a file.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  The Save Data widget considers a dataset provided in the input channel and saves it to a data file with a specified name. It can save the data as a tab-delimited or a comma-separated file.
The widget does not save the data every time it receives a new signal in the input as this would constantly (and, mostly, inadvertently) overwrite the file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Distance Matrix</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/savedistancematrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/savedistancematrix/</guid>
      <description>Save Distance Matrix Saves a distance matrix.
Inputs
 Distances: distance matrix   By clicking Save, you choose from previously saved distance matrices. Alternatively, tick the box on the left side of the Save button and changes will be communicated automatically. By clicking Save as, you save the distance matrix to your computer, you only need to enter the name of the file and click Save. The distance matrix will be saved as type .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Images</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/saveimages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/image-analytics/saveimages/</guid>
      <description>Save Images Save images in the directory structure.
Inputs
 Data: images to save.  Save Images is a simple widget that saves images sent to its input. Images will be saved as separate files in their own directory. When a class is present in the data, images will be saved in subdirectories based on the class variable.
 Attribute containing the path to the image. If Scale images to is ticked, images will be resized to the size used in the selected embedder:  Inception v3: 299x299 SqueezeNet: 227x227 VGG-16: 224x224 VGG-19: 224x224 Painters: 256x256 DeepLoc: 64x64 openface: 256x256  File format to save images in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Model</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/savemodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/savemodel/</guid>
      <description>Save Model Save a trained model to an output file.
Inputs
 Model: trained model   Choose from previously saved models. Save the created model with the Browse icon. Click on the icon and enter the name of the file. The model will be saved to a pickled file.  Save the model.  Example When you want to save a custom-set model, feed the data to the model (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Plot</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/scatterplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/scatterplot/</guid>
      <description>Scatter Plot Scatter plot visualization with explorative analysis and intelligent data visualization enhancements.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data Subset: subset of instances Features: list of attributes  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected  The Scatter Plot widget provides a 2-dimensional scatter plot visualization for continuous attributes. The data is displayed as a collection of points, each having the value of the x-axis attribute determining the position on the horizontal axis and the value of the y-axis attribute determining the position on the vertical axis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Score Cells</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/score_cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/score_cells/</guid>
      <description>Score Cells Add a cell score based on the given set of genes.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Genes: dataset with gene names  Outputs
 Data: dataset with a meta column reporting on cell scores  Score Cells scores the cells (rows) in the input data based on expression of input marker genes. Input data has to include gene names in column headers (as attribute names). The score is computed independently for each cell and is equal to the maximum expression of the marker genes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Score Genes</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/score_genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/score_genes/</guid>
      <description>Score Genes Gene scoring based on statistics of their expression profiles or information content about cell types.
Inputs - Data: input dataset - Scorer: (multiple) prediction model(s)
Outputs - Reduced Data: expression data containing selected genes - Scores: gene scores
The Score Genes widget considers gene expression data with genes in columns and single cell expression profiles in rows. It scores the genes based on statistics of gene expression. For examples, it can sort the genes by their mean expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal Adjustment</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/seasonal_adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/seasonal_adjustment/</guid>
      <description>Seasonal Adjustment Decompose the time series into seasonal, trend, and residual components.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  Outputs
 Time series: Original time series with some additional columns: seasonal component, trend component, residual component, and seasonally adjusted time series.   Length of the season in periods (e.g. 12 for monthly data). Time series decomposition model, additive or multiplicative. The series to seasonally adjust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Select Columns</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/selectcolumns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/selectcolumns/</guid>
      <description>Select Columns Manual selection of data attributes and composition of data domain.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with columns as set in the widget  The Select Columns widget is used to manually compose your data domain. The user can decide which attributes will be used and how. Orange distinguishes between ordinary attributes, (optional) class attributes and meta attributes. For instance, for building a classification model, the domain would be composed of a set of attributes and a discrete class attribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Select Rows</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/selectrows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/selectrows/</guid>
      <description>Select Rows Selects data instances based on conditions over data features.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Matching Data: instances that match the conditions Non-Matching Data: instances that do not match the conditions Data: data with an additional column showing whether a instance is selected  This widget selects a subset from an input dataset, based on user-defined conditions. Instances that match the selection rule are placed in the output Matching Data channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Select by Data Index</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/select-by-data-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/select-by-data-index/</guid>
      <description>Select by Data Index Match instances by index from data subset.
Inputs
 Data: reference data set Data Subset: subset to match  Outputs
 Matching data: subset from reference data set that matches indices from subset data Unmatched data: subset from reference data set that does not match indices from subset data Annotated data: reference data set with an additional column defining matches  Select by Data Index enables matching the data by indices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Organizing Map</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/selforganizingmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/selforganizingmap/</guid>
      <description>Self-Organizing Map Computation of a self-organizing map.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected  A self-organizing map (SOM) is a type of artificial neural network (ANN) that is trained using unsupervised learning to produce a two-dimensional, discretized representation of the data. It is a method to do dimensionality reduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/sentimentanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/sentimentanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment Analysis Predict sentiment from text.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents.  Outputs
 Corpus: A corpus with information on the sentiment of each document.  Sentiment Analysis predicts sentiment for each document in a corpus. It uses Liu Hu and Vader sentiment modules from NLTK. Both of them are lexicon-based. For Liu Hu, you can choose English or Slovenian version.
 Method:  Liu Hu: lexicon-based sentiment analysis (supports English and Slovenian) Vader: lexicon- and rule-based sentiment analysis  Produce a report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sieve Diagram</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/sievediagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/sievediagram/</guid>
      <description>Sieve Diagram Plots a sieve diagram for a pair of attributes.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  A Sieve Diagram is a graphical method for visualizing frequencies in a two-way contingency table and comparing them to expected frequencies under assumption of independence. It was proposed by Riedwyl and Schüpbach in a technical report in 1983 and later called a parquet diagram (Riedwyl and Schüpbach 1994). In this display, the area of each rectangle is proportional to the expected frequency, while the observed frequency is shown by the number of squares in each rectangle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silhouette Plot</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/silhouetteplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/silhouetteplot/</guid>
      <description>Silhouette Plot A graphical representation of consistency within clusters of data.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected  The Silhouette Plot widget offers a graphical representation of consistency within clusters of data and provides the user with the means to visually assess cluster quality. The silhouette score is a measure of how similar an object is to its own cluster in comparison to other clusters and is crucial in the creation of a silhouette plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarity Hashing</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/similarityhashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/similarityhashing/</guid>
      <description>Similarity Hashing Computes documents hashes.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents.  Outputs
 Corpus: Corpus with simhash value as attributes.  Similarity Hashing is a widget that transforms documents into similarity vectors. The widget uses SimHash method from from Moses Charikar.
 Set Simhash size (how many attributes will be on the output, corresponds to bits of information) and shingle length (how many tokens are used in a shingle).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Cell Datasets</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/single_cell_datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/single_cell_datasets/</guid>
      <description>Single Cell Datasets Load a single cell data from an online repository.
Outputs - Data: A single cell dataset containing cells and their gene expression or gene markers.
Single Cell Datasets retrieves a selected data set from the data base server and sends the data to the output. Gene expression data sets include cells in rows and genes in columns. The data set file is downloaded to the local memory, and for subsequent requests instantly available even without the internet connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Cell Preprocess</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/single-cell/single_cell_preprocess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/single-cell/single_cell_preprocess/</guid>
      <description>Single Cell Preprocess Preprocess Single Cell data set.
Inputs - Data: Single cell dataset.
Outputs - Preprocessed Data: Preprocessed dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Mode</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/networks/singlemode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/networks/singlemode/</guid>
      <description>Single Mode Convert multimodal graphs to single modal.
Inputs
 Network: An instance of a bipartite network graph.  Outputs
 Network: An instance of single network graph.  Single Mode works with bipartite networks, where subsets are marked with a binary discrete attribute. The widget outputs a network where nodes represent the selected value (e.g. persons) and edges the remaining value (e.g. event). The widget also works with non-binary discrete attributes, but will treat them as binary (one-versus-all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectra</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/spectra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/spectroscopy/spectra/</guid>
      <description>Spectra Visually explore series of spectra with no spatial information.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data Subset:subset of the data  Outputs
 Selection: selected spectra  The Spectra widget allows visual exploration of multiple spectra. To output some spectra, select them by clicking. For multiple selection, hold the modifier key (Ctrl or Cmd) or use line selection (see the plot options menu). Selected spectra will appear dashed.
 Open the plot options menu A spectrum The X and Y position of the cursor The legend (appears only is spectra are colored)  Navigation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiralogram</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/spiralogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/spiralogram/</guid>
      <description>Spiralogram Visualize variables&amp;rsquo; auto-correlation.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  Visualize time series&amp;rsquo; periodicity in a spiral heatmap.
 Unit of the vertical axis. Options are: years, months, or days (as present in the series), months of year, days of week, days of month, days of year, weeks of year, weeks of month, hours of day, minutes of hour. Unit of the radial axis (options are the same as for (1)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stacking</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/stacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/stacking/</guid>
      <description>Stacking Stack multiple models.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s) Learners: learning algorithm Aggregate: model aggregation method  Outputs
 Learner: aggregated (stacked) learning algorithm Model: trained model  Stacking is an ensemble method that computes a meta model from several base models. The Stacking widget has the Aggregate input, which provides a method for aggregating the input models. If no aggregation input is given the default methods are used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/stochasticgradient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/stochasticgradient/</guid>
      <description>Stochastic Gradient Descent Minimize an objective function using a stochastic approximation of gradient descent.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: stochastic gradient descent learning algorithm Model: trained model  The Stochastic Gradient Descent widget uses stochastic gradient descent that minimizes a chosen loss function with a linear function. The algorithm approximates a true gradient by considering one sample at a time, and simultaneously updates the model based on the gradient of the loss function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test and Score</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/evaluate/testandscore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/evaluate/testandscore/</guid>
      <description>Test and Score Tests learning algorithms on data.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Test Data: separate data for testing Learner: learning algorithm(s)  Outputs
 Evaluation Results: results of testing classification algorithms  The widget tests learning algorithms. Different sampling schemes are available, including using separate test data. The widget does two things. First, it shows a table with different classifier performance measures, such as classification accuracy and area under the curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Guardian</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/guardian-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/guardian-widget/</guid>
      <description>The Guardian Fetching data from The Guardian Open Platform.
Inputs
 None  Outputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents from the Guardian newspaper.  Guardian retrieves articles from the Guardian newspaper via their API. For the widget to work, you need to provide the API key, which you can get at their access platform.
 Insert the API key for the widget to work.   Provide the query and set the time frame from which to retrieve the articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Modelling</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/topicmodelling-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/topicmodelling-widget/</guid>
      <description>Topic Modelling Topic modelling with Latent Dirichlet Allocation, Latent Semantic Indexing or Hierarchical Dirichlet Process.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents.  Outputs
 Corpus: Corpus with topic weights appended. Topics: Selected topics with word weights. All Topics: Token weights per topic.  Topic Modelling discovers abstract topics in a corpus based on clusters of words found in each document and their respective frequency. A document typically contains multiple topics in different proportions, thus the widget also reports on the topic weight per document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transpose</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/data/transpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/data/transpose/</guid>
      <description>Transpose Transposes a data table.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: transposed dataset  Transpose widget transposes data table.
Example This is a simple workflow showing how to use Transpose. Connect the widget to File widget. The output of Transpose is a transposed data table with rows as columns and columns as rows. You can observe the result in a Data Table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/tree/</guid>
      <description>Tree A tree algorithm with forward pruning.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: decision tree learning algorithm Model: trained model  Tree is a simple algorithm that splits the data into nodes by class purity. It is a precursor to Random Forest. Tree in Orange is designed in-house and can handle both discrete and continuous datasets.
It can also be used for both classification and regression tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree Viewer</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/treeviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/treeviewer/</guid>
      <description>Tree Viewer A visualization of classification and regression trees.
Inputs
 Tree: decision tree  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the tree node Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected  This is a versatile widget with 2-D visualization of classification and regression trees. The user can select a node, instructing the widget to output the data associated with the node, thus enabling explorative data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweet Profiler</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/tweetprofiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/tweetprofiler/</guid>
      <description>Tweet Profiler Detect Ekman&amp;rsquo;s, Plutchik&amp;rsquo;s or Profile of Mood States&amp;rsquo; emotions in tweets.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of tweets (or other documents).  Outputs
 Corpus: A corpus with information on the sentiment of each document.  Tweet Profiler retrieves information on sentiment from the server for each given tweet (or document). The widget sends data to the server, where a model computes emotion probabilities and/or scores. The widget support three classifications of emotion, namely Ekman&amp;rsquo;s, Plutchik&amp;rsquo;s and Profile of Mood States (POMS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/twitter-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/twitter-widget/</guid>
      <description>Twitter Fetching data from The Twitter Search API.
Inputs
 None  Outputs
 Corpus: A collection of tweets from the Twitter API.  Twitter widget enables querying tweets through Twitter API. You can query by content, author or both and accumulate results should you wish to create a larger data set. The widget only supports REST API and allows queries for up to two weeks back.
 To begin your queries, insert Twitter key and secret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VAR Model</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/var/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/var/</guid>
      <description>VAR Model Model the time series using vector autoregression (VAR) model.
Inputs
 Time series: Time series as output by As Timeseries widget.  Outputs
 Time series model: The VAR model fitted to input time series. Forecast: The forecast time series. Fitted values: The values that the model was actually fitted to, equals to original values - residuals. Residuals: The errors the model made at each step.  Using this widget, you can model the time series using VAR model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venn Diagram</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/visualize/venndiagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/visualize/venndiagram/</guid>
      <description>Venn Diagram Plots a Venn diagram for two or more data subsets.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: entire data with a column indicating whether an instance was selected or not  The Venn Diagram widget displays logical relations between datasets by showing the number of common data instances (rows) or the number of shared features (columns). Selecting a part of the visualization outputs the corresponding instances or features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volcano Plot</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/volcano_plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/volcano_plot/</guid>
      <description>Volcano Plot Plots significance versus fold-change for gene expression rates.
Inputs - Data: Input data set.
Outputs - Selected Data: Data subset.
Volcano plot is a graphical method for visualizing changes in replicate data. The widget plots a binary logarithm of fold-change on the x-axis versus statistical significance (negative base 10 logarithm of p-value) on the y-axis.
Volcano Plot is useful for a quick visual identification of statistically significant data (genes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/wikipedia-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/wikipedia-widget/</guid>
      <description>Wikipedia Fetching data from MediaWiki RESTful web service API.
Inputs
 None  Outputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents from the Wikipedia.  Wikipedia widget is used to retrieve texts from Wikipedia API and it is useful mostly for teaching and demonstration.
 Query parameters:  Query word list, where each query is listed in a new line. Language of the query. English is set by default. Number of articles to retrieve per query (range 1-25).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word Cloud</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/wordcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/wordcloud/</guid>
      <description>Word Cloud Generates a word cloud from corpus.
Inputs
 Topic: Selected topic. Corpus: A collection of documents.  Outputs
 Corpus: Documents that match the selection. Selected Word: Selected word that can be used as query in Concordance. Word Counts: Words and their weights.  Word Cloud displays tokens in the corpus, their size denoting the frequency of the word in corpus or an average bag of words count, when bag of words features are at the input of the widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word Enrichment</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/text-mining/wordenrichment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/text-mining/wordenrichment/</guid>
      <description>Word Enrichment Word enrichment analysis for selected documents.
Inputs
 Corpus: A collection of documents. Selected Data: Selected instances from corpus.  Outputs
 None  Word Enrichment displays a list of words with lower p-values (higher significance) for a selected subset compared to the entire corpus. Lower p-value indicates a higher likelihood that the word is significant for the selected subset (not randomly occurring in a text). FDR (False Discovery Rate) is linked to p-value and reports on the expected percent of false predictions in the set of predictions, meaning it account for false positives in list of low p-values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo Finance</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/time-series/yahoo_finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/time-series/yahoo_finance/</guid>
      <description>Yahoo Finance Generate time series from Yahoo Finance stock market data.
Outputs
 Time series: Time series table of open, high, low, close (OHLC) prices, volume and adjusted close price.  This widget fetches historical stock market data from Yahoo Finance and outputs it as a time series data table.
 Stock (e.g. GOOG) or index (e.g. DJI) symbol you are interested in. Date range you are interested in. Desired resolution of the time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dictyExpress</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/dicty_express/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/bioinformatics/dicty_express/</guid>
      <description>dictyExpress Gives access to dictyExpress databases.
Inputs - None
Outputs - Data: Selected experiment (time-course gene expression data).
dictyExpress widget gives a direct access to the dictyExpress database. It allows you to download the data from selected experiments in Dictyostelium by Baylor College of Medicine. The widget requires internet connection to work.
 Log into the database to access personal files. Define the output. Genes from experiments can be either in rows or in columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k-Means</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/kmeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/kmeans/</guid>
      <description>k-Means Groups items using the k-Means clustering algorithm.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset  Outputs
 Data: dataset with cluster index as a class attribute  The widget applies the k-Means clustering algorithm to the data and outputs a new dataset in which the cluster index is used as a class attribute. The original class attribute, if it exists, is moved to meta attributes. Scores of clustering results for various k are also shown in the widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kNN</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/model/knn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/model/knn/</guid>
      <description>kNN Predict according to the nearest training instances.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Preprocessor: preprocessing method(s)  Outputs
 Learner: kNN learning algorithm Model: trained model  The kNN widget uses the kNN algorithm that searches for k closest training examples in feature space and uses their average as prediction.
 A name under which it will appear in other widgets. The default name is &amp;ldquo;kNN&amp;rdquo;. Set the number of nearest neighbors, the distance parameter (metric) and weights as model criteria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>t-SNE</title>
      <link>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/tsne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/widget-catalog/unsupervised/tsne/</guid>
      <description>t-SNE Two-dimensional data projection with t-SNE.
Inputs
 Data: input dataset Data Subset: subset of instances  Outputs
 Selected Data: instances selected from the plot Data: data with an additional column showing whether a point is selected  The t-SNE widget plots the data with a t-distributed stochastic neighbor embedding method. t-SNE is a dimensionality reduction technique, similar to MDS, where points are mapped to 2-D space by their probability distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>