<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dask on Orange</title><link>/blog/dask/</link><description>Recent content in dask on Orange</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/dask/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dask all Folks: preparing large datasets</title><link>/blog/2023/2023-10-24-dask-all-folks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/2023-10-24-dask-all-folks/</guid><description>Today, we will delve into the exciting world of Dask once again, and explore how to finally bring your own data into Orange. Or, more precisely, into an experimental version of Orange that supports Dask.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve already set up your data as an Orange Table and you would just like to re-encode it to better support dask, then all you have to do is export it again as a .</description></item><item><title>A dash of Dask</title><link>/blog/2023/2023-08-31-a-dash-of-dask/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/2023-08-31-a-dash-of-dask/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since our last progress update on Dask, and quite a bit has happened since. Most noticeably, we&amp;rsquo;ve got some more visualization widgets working, but I leave that for another blog post. Today, I want to focus on our updated machine-learning methods. K-Means, PCA, Naive Bayes, Linear, and Logistic Regression are now running. Well, maybe not flawlessly, but hey, they work.
Currently, most of Orange&amp;rsquo;s learners wrap existing scikit-learn methods.</description></item><item><title>Orange you going to ask about dask?</title><link>/blog/2022/2022-12-13-dask-table/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/2022-12-13-dask-table/</guid><description>As great as Orange is at simplifying machine learning and bringing it closer to your everyday regular normal guy, it turns out, there are some major drawbacks that stem from it&amp;rsquo;s very inception. This is because Orange is meant to be run on a laptop. A device with just a handful of CPU cores, and maybe a couple of gigabytes of RAM. Due to this ideology we have so far reasoned that nobody in their right mind would want to throw a very large dataset at it.</description></item></channel></rss>