<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computervision on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/computervision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in computervision on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 15:59:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/computervision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Canvas applied to x-ray optics</title>
      <link>/blog/2014/08/26/orange-canvas-applied-to-x-ray-optics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 15:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014/08/26/orange-canvas-applied-to-x-ray-optics/</guid>
      <description>Orange Canvas is being appropriated by guys who would like to use it as graphical environment for simulating x-ray optics.
Manuel Sanchez del Rio, from The European Synchrotron Facility in Grenoble, France, and Luca Rebuffi from Elettra-Sincrotrone, Trieste, Italy, were looking for a tool that would help them integrate the various tools for x-ray optics simulations, like the popular SHADOW and SRW. They discovered that the data workflow paradigm, like the one used in Orange Canvas, fits their needs perfectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange GSoC: Computer vision add-on for Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/05/15/orange-gsoc-computer-vision-add-on-for-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/05/15/orange-gsoc-computer-vision-add-on-for-orange/</guid>
      <description>This summer I got the chance to develop an add-on for Orange that will introduce basic computer vision functionality, as a part of Google Summer of Code.
The add-on will consist of a set of widgets, each with it&amp;rsquo;s own dedicated purpose, which can be seamlessly connected to provide most commonly used image preprocessing functionality.
Here is a list of the widgets:
 Widget for viewing image files (add description) Widget for resizing an image Widget for rotation/flipping of the image Widget for converting the color mode (RGB, HSV, Grayscale etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>