<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>development on Orange</title><link>/blog/development/</link><description>Recent content in development on Orange</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interval Sliders</title><link>/blog/2023/2023-03-10-interval-slider/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/2023-03-10-interval-slider/</guid><description>This post is not about the Heat Map widget. It&amp;rsquo;s about the new double-handled slider at the top of the heatmap. Not about what it does, but about how it does it. The post should be interesting to readers with some knowledge of Qt. Others, who won&amp;rsquo;t understand it, are expected to be impressed by the complexity of implementing something as simple as adding another handle to a slider. On the other hand (wait for the pun!</description></item><item><title>Meet Trubar, a friend of Orange</title><link>/blog/2023/2023-01-17-trubar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/2023-01-17-trubar/</guid><description>Orange has been translated to Slovenian language (no official release yet: rough corners are very much being polished). This will pave the way for translations into other languages.
What do we use? Gettext, right? Wrong. Orange is written in modern Python and uses f-strings for string interpolation. They are great, but don&amp;rsquo;t play well with gettext.
Why gettext doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it If you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard about gettext: gettext is a popular framework for software localization.</description></item><item><title>Compiling Orange 2 on modern Linux</title><link>/blog/2022/2022-01-10-orange2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/2022-01-10-orange2/</guid><description>We abandoned Orange 2 in 2015 because we did not have enough resources to split between maintaining Orange 2 and building the new version from scratch. Orange was due for a rewrite for quite some time. The core of the pre-3 Orange was written mainly in C++. When Orange was conceived, extending Python with C was the only option to make it run fast enough. Orange was designed before NumPy and even before NumPy&amp;rsquo;s predecessors, Numarray and Numeric.</description></item></channel></rss>