<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>release on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in release on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Changing Status Bar</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/3/8/the-changing-status-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/3/8/the-changing-status-bar/</guid>
      <description>Every week on Friday, when the core team of Orange developers meets, we are designing new improvements of Orange&amp;rsquo;s graphical interface. This time, it was the status bar. Well, actually, it was the status bar quite a while ago and required the change of the core widget library, but it is materializing these days and you will see the changes in the next release.
Consider the Neighbors widget. The widget considers the input data and reference data items, and outputs instance form input data that are most similar to the references.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Add-ons Works Again</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/23/installing-add-ons-works-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 08:34:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/23/installing-add-ons-works-again/</guid>
      <description>Dear Orange users,
Some of you might have an issue installing add-ons with the following issue popping up:
xmlrpc.client.Fault: &amp;lt;Fault -32601: &#39;server error; requested method not found&#39;&amp;gt;
This is the result of the migration to a new infrastructure at PyPi, which provides the installation of add-ons. Our team has rallied to adjust the add-on installer so it works with the new and improved service.
In order to make the add-on installer work (again), please download the latest version of Orange (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis: New Features</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/08/04/text-analysis-new-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 11:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/08/04/text-analysis-new-features/</guid>
      <description>As always, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working hard to bring you new functionalities and improvements. Recently, we&amp;rsquo;ve released Orange version 3.4.5 and Orange3-Text version 0.2.5. We focused on the Text add-on since we are lately holding a lot of text mining workshops. The next one will be at Digital Humanities 2017 in Montreal, QC, Canada in a couple of days and we simply could not resist introducing some sexy new features_._
Related: Text Preprocessing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining: version 0.2.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/09/23/text-mining-version-0-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 14:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/09/23/text-mining-version-0-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Orange3-Text has just recently been polished, updated and enhanced! Our GSoC student Alexey has helped us greatly to achieve another milestone in Orange development and release the latest 0.2.0 version of our text mining add-on. The new release, which is already available on PyPi, includes Wikipedia and SimHash widgets and a rehaul of Bag of Words, Topic Modeling and Corpus Viewer.
Wikipedia widget allows retrieving sources from Wikipedia API and can handle multiple queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.3.1 - Updates and Features</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/04/01/version-3-3-1-updates-and-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 12:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/04/01/version-3-3-1-updates-and-features/</guid>
      <description>About a week ago we issued an updated stable release of Orange, version 3.3.1. We&amp;rsquo;ve introduced some new functionalities and improved a few old ones.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s new in this release:
  New widgets: Distance Matrix for visualizing distance measures in a matrix, Distance Transformation for normalization and inversion of distance matrix, Save Distance Matrix and Distance File for saving and loading distances. Last week we also mentioned a really amazing Silhouette Plot, which helps you visually assess cluster quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange 2.5a2 available</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/01/23/orange-2-5a2-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 11:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/01/23/orange-2-5a2-available/</guid>
      <description>Orange 2.5a2 has been uploaded to PyPI. It now includes basic support for multi-label classification (developed during the Google Summer of Code 2011), some new widget icons and documentation for basket format. Release is also tagged on our Bitbucket repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>