<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nomogram on Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/nomogram/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nomogram on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/nomogram/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Models: Workshop in Belgrade</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/2019-11-20-belgrade-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/2019-11-20-belgrade-workshop/</guid>
      <description>On Monday, Blaž and I held a technical tutorial Data Mining through Visual Programming and Interactive Analytics in Orange at this year&amp;rsquo;s edition of Data Science Conference in Belgrade, Serbia. The tutorial explained how to quickly prototype standard data mining and machine learning workflows in Orange and how to interactively explore clustering and classification models. The final part raised an interesting question that we&amp;rsquo;re going to explore in continuation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Customer Segments for Business</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/2019-11-15-telekom-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/2019-11-15-telekom-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Last month we held a workshop for a large Slovenian Telco company. Their two key questions were - what machine learning techniques can we use on our data and how do we explain the models afterwards. So the workshop focused on three use cases - product segmentation, modeling churn, and clustering customers. With any kind of models, especially unsupervised ones, we often get the question - but how can we explain the clusters?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Case Studies with Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/5/18/business-case-studies-with-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/5/18/business-case-studies-with-orange/</guid>
      <description>Previous week Blaž, Robert and I visited Wärtsilä in the lovely Dolina near Trieste, Italy. Wärtsilä is one of the leading designers of lifecycle power solutions for the global marine and energy markets and its subsidiary in Trieste is one of the largest Wärtsilä Group engine production plants. We were there to hold a one-day workshop on data mining and machine learning with the aim to identify relevant use cases in business and show how to address them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>