<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>orange3 on Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/orange3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in orange3 on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 19:11:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/orange3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange is Getting Smarter</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/22/orange-is-getting-smarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 19:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/22/orange-is-getting-smarter/</guid>
      <description>In the past few months, Orange has been getting smarter and sleeker.
Since version 3.15.0, Orange remembers which distinct widgets users like to connect, adjusting the sorting on the widget search menu accordingly. Additionally, there is a new look for the Edit Links window coming soon.
Orange recently implemented a basic form of opt-in usage tracking, specifically targeting how users add widgets to the canvas.
Word cloud of widget popularity in Orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Kickstarter Success</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/08/27/explaining-kickstarter-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 16:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/08/27/explaining-kickstarter-success/</guid>
      <description>On Kickstarter most app ideas don&amp;rsquo;t get funded. But why is that? When we are looking for possible explanations, it is easy to ascribe the failure to the type of the idea.
But what about those rare cases, where an app idea gets funded? Can we figure out why a particular idea succeeded? Our new widget Explain Predictions can do just that - explain why they will succeed. Or at least, explain why the classifier thinks they will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Surveys to Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/06/12/from-surveys-to-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 07:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/06/12/from-surveys-to-orange/</guid>
      <description>Today we have finished a series of workshops for the Ministry of Public Affairs. This was a year-long cooperation and we had many students asking many different questions. There was however one that we talked about a lot. If I have a survey, how do I get it into Orange?
Related: Analyzing Surveys
We are using EnKlik Anketa service, which is a great Slovenian product offering a wide array of options for the creation of surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Script: Managing Data on the Fly</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/05/15/python-script-managing-data-on-the-fly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 09:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/05/15/python-script-managing-data-on-the-fly/</guid>
      <description>Python Script is this mysterious widget most people don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use, even those versed in Python. Python Script is the widget that supplements Orange functionalities with (almost) everything that Python can offer. And it&amp;rsquo;s time we unveil some of its functionalities with a simple example.
Example: Batch Transform the Data There might be a time when you need to apply a function to all your attributes. Say you wish to log-transform their values, as it is common in gene expression data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering of Monet and Manet</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/05/09/clustering-of-monet-and-manet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 08:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/05/09/clustering-of-monet-and-manet/</guid>
      <description>Ever had a hard time telling the difference between Claude Monet and Édouard Manet? Orange can help you cluster these two authors and even more, discover which of Monet&amp;rsquo;s masterpiece is indeed very similar to Manet&amp;rsquo;s! Use Image Analytics add-on and play with it. Here&amp;rsquo;s how:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfreezing Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/05/unfreezing-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 08:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/05/unfreezing-orange/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried Orange with data big enough that some widgets ran for more than a second? Then you have seen it: Orange froze. While the widget was processing, the interface would not respond to any inputs, and there was no way to stop that widget.
Not all the widgets freeze, though! Some widgets, like Test &amp;amp; Score, k-Means, or Image Embedding, do not block. While they are working, we are free to build other parts of the workflow, and these widgets also show their progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single cell analytics workshop at HHMI | Janelia</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/05/single-cell-analytics-workshop-at-hhmi-janelia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 22:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/05/single-cell-analytics-workshop-at-hhmi-janelia/</guid>
      <description>HHMI | Janelia is one of the prettiest researcher campuses I have ever visited. Located in Ashburn, VA, about 20 minutes from Washington Dulles airport, it is conveniently located yet, in a way, secluded from the buzz of the capital. We adored the guest house with a view of the lake, tasty Janelia-style breakfast (hash-browns with two eggs and sausage, plus a bagel with cream cheese) in the on-campus pub, beautifully-designed interiors to foster collaborations and interactions, and late-evening discussions in the in-house pub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange in Kolkata, India</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/11/08/orange-in-kolkata-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 09:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/11/08/orange-in-kolkata-india/</guid>
      <description>We have just completed the hands-on course on data science at one the most famous Indian educational institutions, Indian Statistical Institute. A one week course was invited by Institute&amp;rsquo;s director Prof. Dr. Sanghamitra Bandyopadhyay, and financially supported by the founding of India&amp;rsquo;s Global Initiative of Academic Networks.
Indian Statistical Institute lies in the hearth of old Kolkata. A peaceful oasis of picturesque campus with mango orchards and waterlily lakes was founded by Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network is Back!</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/11/03/neural-network-is-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 12:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/11/03/neural-network-is-back/</guid>
      <description>We know you&amp;rsquo;ve missed it. We&amp;rsquo;ve been getting many requests to bring back Neural Network widget, but we also had many reservations about it.
Neural networks are powerful and great, but to do them right is not straight-forward. And to do them right in the context of a GUI-based visual programming tool like Orange is a twisted double helix of a roller coaster.
Do we make each layer a widget and then stack them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Surveys</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/10/26/analyzing-surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 11:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/10/26/analyzing-surveys/</guid>
      <description>Our streak of workshops continues. This time we taught professionals from public administration how they can leverage data analytics and machine learning to retrieve interesting information from surveys. Thanks to the Ministry of Public Administration, this is only the first in a line of workshops on data science we are preparing for public sector employees.
For this purpose, we have designed EnKlik Anketa widget, which you can find in Prototypes add-on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diving Into Car Registration Data</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/10/13/diving-into-car-registration-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 12:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/10/13/diving-into-car-registration-data/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we presented Orange at the Festival of Open Data, a mini-conference organized by the Slovenian government, dedicated to the promotion of transparent access to government data. In a 10 minute presentation, we showed how Orange can be used to visualize and explore what kinds of vehicles were registered for the first time in Slovenia in 2017.
The original dataset is available at theOPSI portal and it consists of 73 files, one for each month since January 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange at Station Houston</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/09/15/orange-at-station-houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 21:29:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/09/15/orange-at-station-houston/</guid>
      <description>With over 262 member companies, Station Houston is the largest hub for tech startups in Houston.
One of its members is also Genialis, a life science data exploration company that emerged from our lab and is now delivering pipelines and user-friendly apps for analytics in systems biology.
Thanks to the invitation by the director of operations Alex de la Fuente, we gave a seminar on Data Science for Everyone. We spoke about how Orange can support anyone to learn about data science and then use machine learning on their own data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can We Download Orange Faster?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/08/28/can-we-download-orange-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 09:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/08/28/can-we-download-orange-faster/</guid>
      <description>One day Blaž and Janez came to us and started complaining how slow Orange download is in the US. Since they hold a large course at Baylor College of Medicine every year, this causes some frustration.
Related: Introduction to Data Mining Course in Houston
But we have the data and we&amp;rsquo;ve promptly tried to confirm their complaints by analyzing them&amp;hellip; well, in Orange!
First, let us observe the data. We have 4887 recorded download sessions with one meta feature reporting on the country of the download and four features with time, size, speed in bytes and speed in gigabytes of the download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis: New Features</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/08/04/text-analysis-new-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 11:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/08/04/text-analysis-new-features/</guid>
      <description>As always, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working hard to bring you new functionalities and improvements. Recently, we&amp;rsquo;ve released Orange version 3.4.5 and Orange3-Text version 0.2.5. We focused on the Text add-on since we are lately holding a lot of text mining workshops. The next one will be at Digital Humanities 2017 in Montreal, QC, Canada in a couple of days and we simply could not resist introducing some sexy new features_._
Related: Text Preprocessing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Orange Developers</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/07/28/support-orange-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 12:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/07/28/support-orange-developers/</guid>
      <description>Do you love Orange? Do you think it is the best thing since sliced bread? Want to thank all the developers for their hard work?
Nothing says thank you like a fresh supply of ice cream and now you can help us stock our fridge with your generous donations. 🍦🍦🍦
Donate
Support open source software and the team behind Orange. We promise to squander all your contributions purely on ice cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miniconda Installer</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/07/14/miniconda-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 13:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/07/14/miniconda-installer/</guid>
      <description>Orange has a new friend! It&amp;rsquo;s Miniconda, Anaconda&amp;rsquo;s little sister.
For a long time, the idea was to utilize the friendly nature of Miniconda to install Orange dependencies, which often misbehaved on some platforms. Miniconda provides Orange with Python 3.6 and conda installer, which is then used to handle everything Orange needs for proper functioning. So sssssss-mooth!
Miniconda Installer
Please know that our Miniconda installer is in a beta state, but we are inviting adventurous testers to try it and report any bugs they find to our issue tracker [there won&amp;rsquo;t be any of course!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Preprocessing</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/06/19/text-preprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 08:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/06/19/text-preprocessing/</guid>
      <description>In data mining, preprocessing is key. And in text mining, it is the key and the door. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s the most vital step in the analysis.
Related: Text Mining add-on
So what does preprocessing do? Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at an example. Place Corpus widget from Text add-on on the canvas. Open it and load Grimm-tales-selected. As always, first have a quick glance of the data in Corpus Viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers in Traffic Signs</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/25/outliers-in-traffic-signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 07:35:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/25/outliers-in-traffic-signs/</guid>
      <description>Say I am given a collection of images of traffic signs, and would like to find which signs stick out. That is, which traffic signs look substantially different from the others. I would assume that the traffic signs are not equally important and that some were designed to be noted before the others.
I have assembled a small set of regulatory and warning traffic signs and stored the references to their images in a traffic-signs-w.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model replaces Classify and Regression</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/07/model-replaces-classify-and-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 14:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/07/model-replaces-classify-and-regression/</guid>
      <description>Did you recently wonder where did Classification Tree go? Or what happened to Majority?
Orange 3.4.0 introduced a new widget category, Model, which now contains all supervised learning algorithms in one place and replaces the separate Classify and Regression categories.
This, however, was not a mere cosmetic change to the widget hierarchy. We wanted to simplify the interface for new users and make finding an appropriate learning algorithm easier. Moreover, now you can reuse some workflows on different data sets, say housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Analytics: Clustering</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/03/image-analytics-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 12:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/03/image-analytics-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Data does not always come in a nice tabular form. It can also be a collection of text, audio recordings, video materials or even images. However, computers can only work with numbers, so for any data mining, we need to transform such unstructured data into a vector representation.
For retrieving numbers from unstructured data, Orange can use deep network embedders. We have just started to include various embedders in Orange, and for now, they are available for text and images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on InfraOrange</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/03/08/workshop-on-infraorange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 14:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/03/08/workshop-on-infraorange/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the collaboration with synchrotrons Elettra (Trieste) and Soleil (Paris), Orange is getting an add-on InfraOrange, with widgets for analysis of infrared spectra. Its primary users obviously come from these two institutions, hence we organized the first workshop for InfraOrange at one of them.
Some 20 participants spent the first day of the workshop in Trieste learning the basics of Orange and its use for data mining. With Janez at the helm and Marko assisting in the back, we traversed the standard list of visual and statistical techniques and a bit of unsupervised and supervised learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Workshops: Luxembourg, Pavia, Ljubljana</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/03/06/luxembourg-pavia-ljubljana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 21:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/03/06/luxembourg-pavia-ljubljana/</guid>
      <description>February was a month of Orange workshops.
Ljubljana: Biologists We (Tomaž, Martin and I) have started in Ljubljana with a hands-on course for the COST Action FA1405 Systems Biology Training School. This was a four hour workshop with an introduction to classification and clustering, and then with application of machine learning to analysis of gene expression data on a plant called Arabidopsis. The organization of this course has even inspired us for a creation of a new widget GOMapMan Ontology that was added to Bioinformatics add-on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Orange Widget</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/02/23/my-first-orange-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 10:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/02/23/my-first-orange-widget/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I took on a daunting task - programming my first widget. I&amp;rsquo;m not a programmer or a computer science grad, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at Orange code for almost two years now and I thought I could handle it.
I set to create a simple Concordance widget that displays word contexts in a corpus (the widget will be available in the future release). The widget turned out to be a little more complicated than I originally anticipated, but it was a great exercise in programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For When You Want to Transpose a Data Table...</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/02/03/for-when-you-want-to-transpose-a-data-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 13:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/02/03/for-when-you-want-to-transpose-a-data-table/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you need something more. Something different. Something, that helps you look at the world from a different perspective. Sometimes, you simply need to transpose your data.
Since version 3.3.9, Orange has a Transpose widget that flips your data table around. Columns become rows and rows become columns. This is often useful, if you have, say, biological data.
Related: Datasets in Orange Bioinformatics
Today we will play around with brown-selected.tab, a data set on gene expression levels for 79 experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beauty of Random Forest</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/12/22/the-beauty-of-random-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 08:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/12/22/the-beauty-of-random-forest/</guid>
      <description>It is the time of the year when we adore Christmas trees. But these are not the only trees we, at Orange team, think about. In fact, through almost life-long professional deformation of being a data scientist, when I think about trees I would often think about classification and regression trees. And they can be beautiful as well. Not only for their elegance in explaining the hidden patterns, but aesthetically, when rendered in Orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensionality Reduction by Manifold Learning</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/12/12/dimensionality-reduction-by-manifold-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 07:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/12/12/dimensionality-reduction-by-manifold-learning/</guid>
      <description>The new Orange release (v. 3.3.9) welcomed a few wonderful additions to its widget family, including Manifold Learning widget. The widget reduces the dimensionality of the high-dimensional data and is thus wonderful in combination with visualization widgets.
Manifold Learning widget has a simple interface with powerful features.
Manifold Learning widget offers five embedding techniques based on scikit-learn library: t-SNE, MDS, Isomap, Locally Linear Embedding and Spectral Embedding. They each handle the mapping differently and also have a specific set of parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining for Political Scientists</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/11/30/data-mining-for-political-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 08:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/11/30/data-mining-for-political-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Being a political scientist, I did not even hear about data mining before I&amp;rsquo;ve joined Biolab. And naturally, as with all good things, data mining started to grow on me. Give me some data, connect a bunch of widgets and see the magic happen!
But hold on! There are still many social scientists out there who haven&amp;rsquo;t yet heard about the wonderful world of data mining, text mining and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrity Lookalike or How to Make Students Love Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/11/25/celebrity-lookalike-or-how-to-make-students-love-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 14:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/11/25/celebrity-lookalike-or-how-to-make-students-love-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Recently we&amp;rsquo;ve been participating at Days of Computer Science, organized by the Museum of Post and Telecommunications and the Faculty of Computer and Information Science, University of Ljubljana, Slovenia. The project brought together pupils and students from around the country and hopefully showed them what computer science is mostly about. Most children would think programming is just typing lines of code. But it&amp;rsquo;s more than that. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of thinking, a way to solve problems creatively and efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 100 Changemakers in Central and Eastern Europe</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/11/18/top-100-changemakers-in-central-and-eastern-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 13:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/11/18/top-100-changemakers-in-central-and-eastern-europe/</guid>
      <description>Recently Orange and one of its inventors, Blaž Zupan, have been recognized as one of the top 100 changemakers in the region. A 2016 New Europe 100 is an annual list of innovators and entrepreneurs in Central and Eastern Europe highlighting novel approaches to pressing problems.
Orange has been recognized for making data more approachable, which has been our goal from the get-go. The tool is continually being developed with the end user in mind - someone who wants to analyze his/her data quickly, visually, interactively, and efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange at Eurostat&#39;s Big Data Workshop</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/11/02/orange-at-eurostats-big-data-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 12:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/11/02/orange-at-eurostats-big-data-workshop/</guid>
      <description>A Eurostat&amp;rsquo;s Big Data Workshop recently took place in Ljubljana. In a presentation we have showcased Orange as a tool to teach data science.
The meeting was organised by Statistical Office of Slovenia and by Eurostat, a Statistical Office of the European Union, and was a primary gathering of representatives from national statistical institutes joined within European Statistical System. The meeting discussed possibilities that big data offers to modern statistics and the role it could play in statistical offices around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips and Tricks for Using Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/10/17/tips-for-using-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 12:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/10/17/tips-for-using-orange/</guid>
      <description>TIP #1: Follow tutorials and example workflows to get started.
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to start using new software. Where does one start, especially a total novice in data mining? For this exact reason we&amp;rsquo;ve prepared Getting Started With Orange - YouTube tutorials for complete beginners. Example workflows on the other hand can be accessed via Help - Examples.
TIP #2: Make use of Orange documentation.
You can access it in three ways:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Data Mining for Life Scientists</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/10/02/intro-to-data-mining-for-life-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 11:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/10/02/intro-to-data-mining-for-life-scientists/</guid>
      <description>RNA Club Munich has organized Molecular Life of Stem Cells Conference in Ljubljana this past Thursday, Friday and Saturday. They asked us to organize a four-hour workshop on data mining. And here we were: four of us, Ajda, Anze, Marko and myself (Blaz) run a workshop for 25 students with molecular biology and biochemistry background.
We have covered some basic data visualization, modeling (classification) and model scoring, hierarchical clustering and data projection, and finished with a touch of deep-learning by diving into image analysis by deep learning-based embedding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining: version 0.2.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/09/23/text-mining-version-0-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 14:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/09/23/text-mining-version-0-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Orange3-Text has just recently been polished, updated and enhanced! Our GSoC student Alexey has helped us greatly to achieve another milestone in Orange development and release the latest 0.2.0 version of our text mining add-on. The new release, which is already available on PyPi, includes Wikipedia and SimHash widgets and a rehaul of Bag of Words, Topic Modeling and Corpus Viewer.
Wikipedia widget allows retrieving sources from Wikipedia API and can handle multiple queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining Course in Houston #2</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/09/15/data-mining-in-houston-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 13:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/09/15/data-mining-in-houston-2/</guid>
      <description>This was already the second installment of Introduction to Data Mining Course at Baylor College of Medicine in Houston, Texas. Just like the last year, the course was packed. About 50 graduate students, post-docs and a few faculty attended, making the course one of the largest elective PhD courses from over a hundred offered at this prestigious medical school.
The course was designed for students with little or no experience in data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Gradient Descent</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/25/visualizing-gradient-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 11:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/25/visualizing-gradient-descent/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest blog from the Google Summer of Code project.
Gradient Descent was implemented as a part of my Google Summer of Code project and it is available in the Orange3-Educational add-on. It simulates gradient descent for either Logistic or Linear regression, depending on the type of the input data. Gradient descent is iterative approach to optimize model parameters that minimize the cost function. In machine learning, the cost function corresponds to prediction error when the model is used on the training data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making recommendations</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/19/making-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 20:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/19/making-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest blog from the Google Summer of Code project.
Recommender systems are everywhere, we can find them on YouTube, Amazon, Netflix, iTunes,&amp;hellip; This is because they are crucial component in a competitive retail services.
How can I know what you may like if I have almost no information about you? The answer: taking Collaborative filtering (CF) approaches. Basically, this means to combine all the little knowledge we have about users and/or items in order to build a grid of knowledge with which we make recommendation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of Classification Probabilities</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/16/polynomial-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 17:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/16/polynomial-classification/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest blog from the Google Summer of Code project.
Polynomial Classification widget is implemented as a part of my Google Summer of Code project along with other widgets in educational add-on (see my previous blog). It visualizes probabilities for two-class classification (target vs. rest) using color gradient and contour lines, and it can do so for any Orange learner.
Here is an example workflow. The data comes from the File widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive k-Means</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/12/interactive-k-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 12:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/12/interactive-k-means/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest blog from the Google Summer of Code project.
As a part of my Google Summer of Code project I started developing educational widgets and assemble them in an Educational Add-On for Orange. Educational widgets can be used by students to understand how some key data mining algorithms work and by teachers to demonstrate the working of these algorithms.
Here I describe an educational widget for interactive k-means clustering, an algorithm that splits the data into clusters by finding cluster centroids such that the distance between data points and their corresponding centroid is minimized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rule Induction (Part I - Scripting)</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/05/rule-induction-part-i-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 11:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/05/rule-induction-part-i-scripting/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest blog from the Google Summer of Code project.
We’ve all heard the saying, “Rules are meant to be broken.” Regardless of how you might feel about the idea, one thing is certain. Rules must first be learnt. My 2016 Google Summer of Code project revolves around doing just that. I am developing classification rule induction techniques for Orange, and here describing the code currently available in the pull request and that will become part of official distribution in an upcoming release 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagorean Trees and Forests</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/07/29/pythagorean-trees-and-forests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 11:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/07/29/pythagorean-trees-and-forests/</guid>
      <description>Classification Trees are great, but how about when they overgrow even your 27&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; screen? Can we make the tree fit snugly onto the screen and still tell the whole story? Well, yes we can.
Pythagorean Tree widget will show you the same information as Classification Tree, but way more concisely. Pythagorean Trees represent nodes with squares whose size is proportionate to the number of covered training instances. Once the data is split into two subsets, the corresponding new squares form a right triangle on top of the parent square.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Analysis with Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/07/18/network-analysis-with-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 13:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/07/18/network-analysis-with-orange/</guid>
      <description>Visualizing relations between data instances can tell us a lot about our data. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this works in Orange. We have a data set on machine learning and data mining conferences and journals, with the number of shared authors for each publication venue reported. We can estimate similarity between two conferences using the author profile of a conference: two conference would be similar if they attract the same authors. The data set is already 9 years old, but obviously, it&amp;rsquo;s about the principle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rehaul of Text Mining Add-On</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/07/05/rehaul-of-text-mining-add-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 06:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/07/05/rehaul-of-text-mining-add-on/</guid>
      <description>Google Summer of Code is progressing nicely and some major improvements are already live! Our students have been working hard and today we&amp;rsquo;re thanking Alexey for his work on Text Mining add-on. Two major tasks before the midterms were to introduce Twitter widget and rehaul Preprocess Text. Twitter widget was designed to be a part of our summer school program and it worked beautifully. We&amp;rsquo;ve introduced youngsters to the world of data mining through social networks and one of the most exciting things was to see whether we can predict the author from the tweet content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripting with Time Variable</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/06/10/scripting-with-time-variable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 12:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/06/10/scripting-with-time-variable/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s always fun to play around with data. And since Orange can, as of a few months ago, read temporal data, we decided to parse some data we had and put it into Orange.
TimeVariable is an extended class of continuous variable and it works with properly formated ISO standard datetime (Y-M-D h:m:s). Oftentimes our original data is not in the right format and needs to be edited first, so Orange can read it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association Rules in Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/04/25/association-rules-in-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 07:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/04/25/association-rules-in-orange/</guid>
      <description>Orange is welcoming back one of its more exciting add-ons: Associate! Association rules can help the user quickly and simply discover the underlying relationships and connections between data instances. Yeah!
The add-on currently has two widgets: one for Association Rules and the other for Frequent Itemsets. With Frequent Itemsets we first check frequency of items and itemsets in our transaction matrix. This tell us which items (products) and itemsets are the most frequent in our data, so it would make a lot of sense focusing on these products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.3.1 - Updates and Features</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/04/01/version-3-3-1-updates-and-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 12:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/04/01/version-3-3-1-updates-and-features/</guid>
      <description>About a week ago we issued an updated stable release of Orange, version 3.3.1. We&amp;rsquo;ve introduced some new functionalities and improved a few old ones.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s new in this release:
  New widgets: Distance Matrix for visualizing distance measures in a matrix, Distance Transformation for normalization and inversion of distance matrix, Save Distance Matrix and Distance File for saving and loading distances. Last week we also mentioned a really amazing Silhouette Plot, which helps you visually assess cluster quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All I See is Silhouette</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/03/23/all-i-see-is-silhouette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 09:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/03/23/all-i-see-is-silhouette/</guid>
      <description>Silhouette plot is such a nice method for visually assessing cluster quality and the degree of cluster membership that we simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to get it into Orange3. And now we did.
What this visualization displays is the average distance between instances within the cluster and instances in the nearest cluster. For a given data instance, the silhouette close to 1 indicates that the data instance is close to the center of the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overfitting and Regularization</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/03/12/overfitting-and-regularization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 16:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/03/12/overfitting-and-regularization/</guid>
      <description>A week ago I used Orange to explain the effects of regularization. This was the second lecture in the Data Mining class, the first one was on linear regression. My introduction to the benefits of regularization used a simple data set with a single input attribute and a continuous class. I drew a data set in Orange, and then used Polynomial Regression widget (from Prototypes add-on) to plot the linear fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange at Google Summer of Code 2016</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/03/03/orange-at-google-summer-of-code-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 08:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/03/03/orange-at-google-summer-of-code-2016/</guid>
      <description>Orange team is extremely excited to be a part of this year&amp;rsquo;s Google Summer of Code! GSoC is a great opportunity for students around the world to spend their summer contributing to an open-source software, gaining experience and earning money.
Accepted students will help us develop Orange (or other chosen OSS project) from May to August. Each student is expected to select and define a project of his/her interest and will be ascribed a mentor to guide him/her through the entire process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange YouTube Tutorials</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/01/04/orange-youtube-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 08:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/01/04/orange-youtube-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming, but finally we&amp;rsquo;ve created out our first set of YouTube tutorials. In a series &amp;lsquo;Getting Started with Orange&amp;rsquo; we will walk through our software step-by-step. You will learn how to create a workflow, load your data in different formats, visualize and explore the data. These tutorials are meant for complete beginners in both Orange and data mining and come with some handy tricks that will make using Orange very easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color it!</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/12/28/color-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 10:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/12/28/color-it/</guid>
      <description>Holiday season is upon us and even the Orange team is in a festive mood. This is why we made a Color widget!
This fascinating artsy widget will allow you to play with your data set in a new and exciting way. No more dull visualizations and default color schemes! Set your own colors the way YOU want it to! Care for some magical cyan-to-magenta? Or do you prefer a more festive red-to-green?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report is back! (and better than ever)</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/12/11/report-is-back-and-better-than-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 09:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/12/11/report-is-back-and-better-than-ever/</guid>
      <description>I’m sure you’d agree that reporting your findings when analyzing the data is crucial. Say you have a couple of interesting predictions that you’ve tested with several methods many times and you’d like to share that with the world. Here’s how.
Save Graph just got company - a Report button! Report works in most widgets, apart from the very obvious ones that simply transmit or display the data (Python Scripting, Edit Domain, Image Viewer, Predictions…).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining our own data</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/11/27/mining-our-own-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 08:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/11/27/mining-our-own-data/</guid>
      <description>Recently we&amp;rsquo;ve made a short survey that was, upon Orange download, asking people how they found out about Orange, what was their data mining level and where do they work. The main purpose of this is to get a better insight into our user base and to figure out what is the profile of people interested in trying Orange.
Here we have some preliminary results that we&amp;rsquo;ve managed to gather in the past three weeks or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghostbusters</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/10/30/ghostbusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 15:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/10/30/ghostbusters/</guid>
      <description>Ok, we’ve just recently stumbled across an interesting article on how to deal with non normal (non-Gaussian distributed) data. We have an absolutely paranormal data set of 20 persons with weight, height, paleness, vengefulness, habitation and age attributes (download).
Let’s check the distribution in Distributions widget.
Our first attribute is “Weight” and we see a little hump on the left. Otherwise the data would be normally distributed. Ok, so perhaps we have a few children in the data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL for Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/10/19/sql-for-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 12:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/10/19/sql-for-orange/</guid>
      <description>We bet you&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to use your SQL data in Orange, but you might not be quite sure how to do it. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, we&amp;rsquo;re coming to the rescue.
The key to SQL files is installation of &amp;lsquo;psycopg2&amp;rsquo; library in Python.
WINDOWS
Go to this website and download psycopg2 package. Once your .whl file has downloaded, go to the file directory and run command prompt. Enter “pip install [file name]” and run it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learners in Python</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/10/16/learners-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 08:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/10/16/learners-in-python/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve already written about classifying instances in Python. However, it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to have a comprehensive list of classifiers and a step-by-step procedure at hand.
TRAINING THE CLASSIFIER
We start with simply importing Orange module into Python and loading our data set.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import Orange &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; data = Orange.data.Table(&amp;quot;titanic&amp;quot;)  We are using &amp;lsquo;titanic.tab&amp;rsquo; data. You can load any data set you want, but it does have to have a categorical class variable (for numeric targets use regression).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining Course in Houston</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/10/09/data-mining-course-in-houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 06:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/10/09/data-mining-course-in-houston/</guid>
      <description>We have just completed an Introduction to Data Mining, a graduate course at Baylor College of Medicine in Texas, Houston. The course was given in September and consisted of seven two-hour lectures, each one followed with a homework assignment. The course was attended by about 40 students and some faculty and research staff.
This was a challenging course. The audience was new to data mining, and we decided to teach them with the newest, third version of Orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hubbing with the Hub widget</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/09/11/hubbing-with-hub-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 06:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/09/11/hubbing-with-hub-widget/</guid>
      <description>So you have painted two data sets and loaded another one from a file, and now you are testing predictions of logistic regression, classification trees and SVM on it? Tired of having to reconnect the Paint data widget and the File widget back and forth whenever you switch between them?
Say no more! Look no further! Here is the new Hub widget!
Hub widget is the most versatile widget available so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Widget Documentation</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/09/04/updated-widget-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/09/04/updated-widget-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Happy news for all passionate Orange users! We’ve uploaded documentation for our Orange 3 widget selection.
Right click and select &amp;ldquo;Help&amp;rdquo; or press F1.
** **
It’s easy to use. To learn more about a particular wigdet, click on the widget. Either use right click and select “Help” or press F1. A new window will open with a widget description and an example for its use. There are also screenshots included as visual help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatter Plot Projection Rank</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/08/28/scatter-plot-projection-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 14:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/08/28/scatter-plot-projection-rank/</guid>
      <description>One of the nicest and surely most useful visualization widgets in Orange is Scatter Plot. The widget displays a 2-D plot, where x and y-axes are two attributes from the data.
2-dimensional scatter plot visualization
Orange 2.7 has a wonderful functionality called VizRank, that is now implemented also in Orange 3. Rank Projections functionality enables you to find interesting attribute pairs by scoring their average classification accuracy. Click ‘Start Evaluation’ to begin ranking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying instances with Orange in Python</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/08/14/classifying-instances-with-orange-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 12:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/08/14/classifying-instances-with-orange-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Last week we showed you how to create your own data table in Python shell. Now we’re going to take you a step further and show you how to easily classify data with Orange.
First we’re going to create a new data table with 10 fruits as our instances.
import Orange from Orange.data import * color = DiscreteVariable(&amp;quot;color&amp;quot;, values=[&amp;quot;orange&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;green&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;yellow&amp;quot;])calories = ContinuousVariable(&amp;quot;calories&amp;quot;) fiber = ContinuousVariable(&amp;quot;fiber&amp;quot;) fruit = DiscreteVariable(&amp;quot;fruit&amp;quot;, values=[&amp;quot;orange&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;apple&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;peach&amp;quot;]) domain = Domain([color, calories, fiber], class_vars=fruit) data=Table(domain, [&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; [&amp;quot;green&amp;quot;, 4, 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explorative data analysis with Hierarchical Clustering</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/07/20/explorative-data-analysis-with-hierarchical-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 07:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/07/20/explorative-data-analysis-with-hierarchical-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Today we will write about cluster analysis with Hierarchical Clustering widget. We use a well-known Iris data set, which contains 150 Iris flowers, each belonging to one of the three species (setosa, versicolor and virginica). To an untrained eye the three species are very alike, so how could we best tell them apart? The data set contains measurements of sepal and petal dimensions (width and length) and we assume that these gives rise to interesting clustering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support vectors output in SVM widget</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/07/03/support-vectors-output-in-svm-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 06:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/07/03/support-vectors-output-in-svm-widget/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that the widget for support vector machines (SVM) classifier can output support vectors? And that you can visualise these in any other Orange widget? In the context of all other data sets, this could provide some extra insight into how this popular classification algorithm works and what it actually does.
Ideally, that is, in the case of linear seperability, support vector machines (SVM) find a **hyperplane with the largest margin **to any data instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Fusion Tutorial at the [BC]^2</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/06/08/data-fusion-tutorial-at-the-bc2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 15:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/06/08/data-fusion-tutorial-at-the-bc2/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to host a three-hour tutorial on data fusion at the Basel Computational Biology Conference. To this end we have prepared a series of short lectures notes that accompany the recently developed Data Fusion Add-on for Orange.
We design the tutorial for data mining researchers and molecular biologists with interest in large-scale data integration. In the tutorial we focus on collective latent factor models, a popular class of approaches for data fusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Fusion Add-on for Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/06/05/data-fusion-add-on-for-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 06:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/06/05/data-fusion-add-on-for-orange/</guid>
      <description>Orange is about to get even more exciting! We have created a prototype add-on for data fusion, which will certainly be of interest to many users. Data fusion brings large heterogeneous data sets together to create sensible clusters of related data instances and provides a platform for predictive modelling and recommendation systems.
This widget set can be used either to recommend you the next movie to watch based on your demographic characteristics, movies you gave high scores to, your preferred genre, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel files in Orange 3.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/05/29/excel-files-in-orange-3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 11:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/05/29/excel-files-in-orange-3-0/</guid>
      <description>Orange 3.0 version comes with an exciting feature that will simplify reading your data. If the old Orange required conversion from Excel into either tab-delimited or comma-separated files, the new version allows you to open plain .xlsx format data sets in the program. Naturally, the .txt and .csv files are still readable in Orange, so feel free to use data sets in any of the above-mentioned formats.
Since Orange 3.0 is still in the development mode, you will find a smaller selection of widgets available at the moment, but give it a go and see how it works for Excel type data and whether the existing widgets are sufficient for your data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Fridays</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/05/22/orange-fridays/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 14:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/05/22/orange-fridays/</guid>
      <description>You might think “casual Fridays” are the best thing since sliced bread. But what if I were to tell you we have “Orange Fridays” at our lab, where lab members focus solely on debugging Orange software and making improvements to existing features. This is because the new developing version of Orange (3.0) still needs certain widgets to be implemented, such as net explorer, radviz, and survey plot.
But there’s more. We are currently hosting an expert on data fusion from the University of Leuven, prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with SQL data in Orange 3</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/05/05/working-with-sql-data-in-orange-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 07:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/05/05/working-with-sql-data-in-orange-3/</guid>
      <description>Orange 3 is slowly, but steadily, gaining support for working with data stored in a SQL database. The main focus is to allow huge data sets that do not fit into RAM to be analyzed and visualized efficiently. Many widgets already recognize the type of input data and perform the necessary computations intelligently. This means that data is not downloaded from the database and analyzed locally, but is retained on the remote server, with the computation tasks translated into SQL queries and offloaded to the database engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange in Pavia, Italy</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/02/19/orange-in-pavia-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 15:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/02/19/orange-in-pavia-italy/</guid>
      <description>These days, we (Blaz Zupan and Marinka Zitnik, with full background support of entire Bioinformatics Lab) are running a three-day course on Data Mining in Python. Riccardo Bellazzi, a professor at University of Pavia, a world-renown researcher in biomedical informatics, and most of all, a great friend, has invited us to run the elective course for Pavia&amp;rsquo;s grad students. The enrollment was, he says, overwhelming, as with over 50 students this is by far the best attended grad course at Pavia&amp;rsquo;s faculty of engineering in the past years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Orange 3</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/02/12/towards-orange-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 11:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/02/12/towards-orange-3/</guid>
      <description>We are rushing, full speed ahead, towards Orange 3. A complete revamp of Orange in Python 3 changes its data model to that of numpy, making Orange compatible with an array of Python-based data analytics. We are rewriting all the widgets for visual programming as well. We have two open fronts: the scripting part, and the widget part. So much to do, but it is going well: the closed tasks for widgets are those on the left of Anze (the board full of sticky notes), and those open, in minority, are on Anze&amp;rsquo;s right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading your data</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/01/18/loading-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 17:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/01/18/loading-your-data/</guid>
      <description>By a popular demand, we have just published a tutorial on how to load the data table into Orange. Besides its own .tab format, Orange can load any tab or comma delimited data set. The details are though in writing header rows that tell Orange about the type and domain of each attribute. The tutorial is a step-by-step description on how to do this and how to transfer the data from popular spreadsheet programs like Excel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange and SQL</title>
      <link>/blog/2014/05/29/orange-and-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014/05/29/orange-and-sql/</guid>
      <description>Orange 3.0 will also support working with data stored in a database.
While we have already talked about this some time ago, we here describe some technical details for anybody interested. This is not a thorough tecnical report, its purpose is only to provide an impression about the architecture of the upcoming version of Orange.
So, data tables in Orange 3.0 can refer to data in the working memory or in the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange and AXLE project</title>
      <link>/blog/2013/09/02/orange-and-axle-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 21:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013/09/02/orange-and-axle-project/</guid>
      <description>Our group at University of Ljubljana is a partner in the EU 7FP project Advanced Analytics for Extremely Large European Databases (AXLE). The project is particularly interesting because of the diverse partners that cover the entire vertical, from studying hardware architectures that would better support extremely large databases (University of Manchester, Barcelona Supercomputing Center) to making the necessary adjustments related to speed and security of databases (2ndQuadrant) to data analytics (our group) to handling and analyzing real data and decision making (Portavita).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing joint entropy (in Python)</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/06/15/computing-joint-entropy-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 13:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/06/15/computing-joint-entropy-in-python/</guid>
      <description>How I wrote a beautiful, general, and super fast joint entropy method (in Python).
def entropy(*X): return = np.sum(-p * np.log2(p) if p &amp;gt; 0 else 0 for p in (np.mean(reduce(np.logical_and, (predictions == c for predictions, c in zip(X, classes)))) for classes in itertools.product(*[set(x) for x in X])))  I started with the method to compute the entropy of a single variable. Input is a numpy array with discrete values (either integers or strings).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDnuggets is asking if you have been using Orange lately</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/05/19/kdnuggets-is-asking-if-you-have-been-using-orange-lately/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 23:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/05/19/kdnuggets-is-asking-if-you-have-been-using-orange-lately/</guid>
      <description>KDnuggets, one of leading data mining community websites, is having its yearly poll asking its visitors which analytics/data mining software they used in the past 12 months. Among listed is also Orange, our fruity visually pleasing open source pythonic data mining suite. So we are asking you, have you been using Orange lately, that is, in the past 12 months? How do you feel about telling that to the world?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange badges are here!</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/09/04/orange-badges-are-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2011 03:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/09/04/orange-badges-are-here/</guid>
      <description>Orange badges are here! They come in two flavors. Tasty!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange T-shirts</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/06/24/orange-t-shirts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 10:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/06/24/orange-t-shirts/</guid>
      <description>If you maybe missed on our Facebook page: we have made our own fruity t-shirts. They are simply awesome and show to everybody around you that you have a taste! Just check the handsomeness:
We will be selling them on the website soon for $15 (shipping costs included), but if you want to have one (or more) in advance, drop us a line and we will see what we can do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>