<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>update on Orange</title><link>/blog/update/</link><description>Recent content in update on Orange</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fall Season Brings Fresh Content to the Introduction to Data Science Series</title><link>/blog/2023/2023-09-01-announcement-nomogram/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/2023-09-01-announcement-nomogram/</guid><description>What better time than the charming fall season to bring to light a long-awaited new batch of videos to our Introduction to Data Science Series. The crisp air and the gentle rustle of leaves create the perfect backdrop for staying in with a hot drink and diving into a new chapter of data analysis and processing.
In the video series so far, we have covered exploratory data analysis, clustering, dimensionality reduction with PCA, t-SNE, and MDS, as well as introduction to classification with trees, forests, and logistic regression.</description></item><item><title>Text Workshops in Ljubljana</title><link>/blog/2018/09/11/text-workshops-in-ljubljana/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 13:49:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2018/09/11/text-workshops-in-ljubljana/</guid><description>In the past month, we had two workshops that focused on text mining. The first one, Faksi v praksi, was organized by the University of Ljubljana Career Centers, where high school students learned about what we do at the Faculty of Computer and Information Science. We taught them what text mining is and how to group a collection of documents in Orange. The second one took on a more serious note, as the public sector employees joined us for the third set of workshops from the Ministry of Public Affairs.</description></item><item><title>Installing Add-ons Works Again</title><link>/blog/2018/04/23/installing-add-ons-works-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 08:34:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2018/04/23/installing-add-ons-works-again/</guid><description>Dear Orange users,
Some of you might have an issue installing add-ons with the following issue popping up:
xmlrpc.client.Fault: &amp;lt;Fault -32601: 'server error; requested method not found'&amp;gt;
This is the result of the migration to a new infrastructure at PyPi, which provides the installation of add-ons. Our team has rallied to adjust the add-on installer so it works with the new and improved service.
In order to make the add-on installer work (again), please download the latest version of Orange (3.</description></item><item><title>Model replaces Classify and Regression</title><link>/blog/2017/04/07/model-replaces-classify-and-regression/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 14:27:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2017/04/07/model-replaces-classify-and-regression/</guid><description>Did you recently wonder where did Classification Tree go? Or what happened to Majority?
Orange 3.4.0 introduced a new widget category, Model, which now contains all supervised learning algorithms in one place and replaces the separate Classify and Regression categories.
This, however, was not a mere cosmetic change to the widget hierarchy. We wanted to simplify the interface for new users and make finding an appropriate learning algorithm easier. Moreover, now you can reuse some workflows on different data sets, say housing.</description></item><item><title>Orange 2.7</title><link>/blog/2013/05/25/orange-2-7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 10:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2013/05/25/orange-2-7/</guid><description>Orange 2.7 is out with a major update in the visual programming environment. Redesigned interface, new widgets, welcome screen with workflow browser. Text annotation and arrow lines in workspace. Preloaded workflows with annotations. Widget menu and search can now be activated through key press (open the Settings to make this option available). Extended or minimised widget tab. Improved widget browsing. Enjoy!</description></item></channel></rss>