<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>confusion matrix on Orange</title><link>/blog/confusion-matrix/</link><description>Recent content in confusion matrix on Orange</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/confusion-matrix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Confusion matrix for regression?</title><link>/blog/2022/2022-05-20-regression-results/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/2022-05-20-regression-results/</guid><description>It is easy to inspect misclassifications in the Confusion Matrix widget when building classification models. One can even click on misclassified instances, output them and observe them in various visualizations. But what about regression? Predicting numeric values doesn&amp;rsquo;t even allow connecting Confusion Matrix, nor would it make sense. So how can one inspect prediction error for regression tasks?
Let us take the well-known housing data set from the File widget. The dataset has 506 instances of houses described with 13 variables and a regression target variable MEDV (median value of homes in 1000$).</description></item><item><title>On Expected Vomiting Time</title><link>/blog/2019/2019-09-28-on-expected-vomiting-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2019/2019-09-28-on-expected-vomiting-time/</guid><description>We just finished a lecture and a student came with a question. The lecture was, in short, about how predictive models compute probabilities; to use a model for making decisions, we must find a threshold that will minimize the cost, maximize the profit, strike a good balance between sensitivity and specificity, or increase the general human well-being in some other way. So this student came with a question about something I didn&amp;rsquo;t explain well, and she gave me one last chance.</description></item></channel></rss>