<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infrared Spectra on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/infrared-spectra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infrared Spectra on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 07:32:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/infrared-spectra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange in Space</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/09/21/orange-in-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 07:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/09/21/orange-in-space/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that Orange has already been to space? Rosario Brunetto (IAS-Orsay, France) has been working on the analysis of infrared images of asteroid Ryugu as a member of the JAXA Hayabusa2 team. The Hayabusa2 asteroid sample-return mission aims to retrieve data and samples from the near-Earth Ryugu asteroid and analyze its composition. Hayabusa2 arrived at Ryugu on June 27 and while the spacecraft will return to Earth with a sample only in late 2020, the mission already started collecting and sending back the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange with Spectroscopy Add-on Workshop</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/28/orange-with-spectroscopy-add-on-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 10:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/28/orange-with-spectroscopy-add-on-workshop/</guid>
      <description>We have just concluded our enhanced Introduction to Data Science workshop, which included several workflows for spectroscopy analysis. Spectroscopy add-on is intended for the analysis of spectral data and it is just as fun as our other add-ons (if not more!).
We will prove it with a simple classification workflow. First, install Spectroscopy add-on from Options - Add-ons menu in Orange. Restart Orange for the add-on to appear. Great, you are ready for some spectral analysis!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on InfraOrange</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/03/08/workshop-on-infraorange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 14:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/03/08/workshop-on-infraorange/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the collaboration with synchrotrons Elettra (Trieste) and Soleil (Paris), Orange is getting an add-on InfraOrange, with widgets for analysis of infrared spectra. Its primary users obviously come from these two institutions, hence we organized the first workshop for InfraOrange at one of them.
Some 20 participants spent the first day of the workshop in Trieste learning the basics of Orange and its use for data mining. With Janez at the helm and Marko assisting in the back, we traversed the standard list of visual and statistical techniques and a bit of unsupervised and supervised learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>