<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>text mining on Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/text-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in text mining on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/text-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Analysis of Documents</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/2021-09-17-semantic-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/2021-09-17-semantic-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Our recent project with the Ministry of Public Administration comprises building a semantic analysis pipeline in Orange, enabling the users to quickly and efficiently explore the content of documents, compare a subset against the corpus, extract keywords, and semantically explore document maps. If this sounds too vague, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick demo on how to perform semantic analysis in Orange.
First, we will use the pre-prepared corpus of proposals to the government, which you can download here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New in Orange: Support for CONLL-U files</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/2021-09-15-connlu-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/2021-09-15-connlu-files/</guid>
      <description>CONLL-U files are ubiquitous in text mining and natural language processing. They can hold a great deal of linguistic data, specifically sentence boundaries, word lemmas, universal POS tags, language specific POS tag, morphological features, dependency relations, named entities, and so on. This is how a typical CONLL-U file looks like.
# sent_id = ParlaMint-GB_2021-01-05-lords.seg2.2 # text = The Hybrid Sitting of the House will now begin. 1 The the DET DT Definite=Def|PronType=Art 2 det _ NER=O 2 Hybrid hybrid NOUN NN Number=Sing 9 nsubj _ NER=O 3 Sitting sit VERB VBG VerbForm=Ger 2 acl _ NER=O 4 of of ADP IN _ 6 case _ NER=O 5 the the DET DT Definite=Def|PronType=Art 6 det _ NER=O 6 House House PROPN NNP Number=Sing 3 obl _ NER=B-ORG 7 will will VERB MD VerbForm=Fin 9 aux _ NER=O 8 now now ADV RB _ 9 advmod _ NER=O 9 begin begin VERB VB VerbForm=Inf 0 root _ NER=O|SpaceAfter=No 10 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Story Arcs with Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/2021-04-16-story-arcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/2021-04-16-story-arcs/</guid>
      <description>Reading is fun because it takes you on a journey. Mostly, it is a journey of emotions as you live and breathe with the protagonist and her adventures. Today, we will have a look at how to detect sentiment in a story, plot story arcs and analyze the content of the key segments in a corpus.
Related: Text Workshops in Ljubljana
We will be using a corpus of Anderson&amp;rsquo;s tales, which is available in the Corpus widget (data set anderson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observing Word Distribution</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/2021-01-27-word-distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/2021-01-27-word-distribution/</guid>
      <description>In text mining, one of key tasks is understanding and inspecting the corpus. It makes it easier to determine the preprocessing techniques and downstream analysis (the selection of document frequency weights, topic modelling technique, lemmatization and so on).
Even though Orange sometimes doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a widget for a specific task, the said task can be achieved with a combination of widgets and their outputs. Let us look at an example of word distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to identify fake news with document embeddings</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/2020-10-15-document-embedders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/2020-10-15-document-embedders/</guid>
      <description>Text is described by the sequence of character. Since every machine learning algorithm needs numbers, we need to transform it into vectors of real numbers before we can continue with the analysis. To do this, we can use various approaches. Orange currently offers bag-of-words approach and now also Document embedding by fastText. In this post, we explain what document embedding is, why it is useful, and show its usage on the classification example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Video Tutorials on Text Mining</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/2020-09-28-text-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/2020-09-28-text-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>In July, we were pleasantly surprised to be awarded a NumFocus Small Development Grant, which is intended to support small tasks in open source projects they sponsor. We decided to extend our text mining tutorials with four new videos, which cover the recent additions to the Text Mining add-on. Our YouTube channel already has a playlist for getting started with Orange and several specialized playlists for learning spectroscopy, single-cell analysis, text mining and image analytics with Orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Story Arcs with Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/2020-07-27-story-arcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/2020-07-27-story-arcs/</guid>
      <description>Reading is fun because it takes you on a journey. Mostly, it is a journey of emotions as you live and breathe with the protagonist and her adventures. Today, we will have a look at how to detect sentiment in a story, plot story arcs and analyze the content of the key segments in a corpus.
Related: Text Workshops in Ljubljana
We will be using a corpus of Anderson&amp;rsquo;s tales, which is available in the Corpus widget (data set anderson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Made Easy: How To Identify Hate Comments with AI</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/2019-07-02-data-science-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/2019-07-02-data-science-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>The IdeenExpo is a biennial participatory event for children, adolescents and young adults taking place in Hanover, Germany. Companies, research organizations, schools and universities participate to show young people the possibilities of the modern working world and gain their interest in technologies and natural sciences. As a part of one of the biggest research-computing-centers in North Germany the GWDG (Gesellschaft für wissenschaftliche Datenverarbeitung mbh Göttingen) took a part in that event to present the possibilities of Data Science and how its methods can be used in different areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining for Anthropologists?</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/06/data-mining-for-anthropologists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 11:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/06/data-mining-for-anthropologists/</guid>
      <description>This weekend we were in Lisbon, Portugal, at the Why the World Needs Anthropologists conference, an event that focuses on applied anthropology, design, and how soft skills can greatly benefit the industry. I was there to hold a workshop on Data Ethnography, an approach that tries to combine methods from data science and anthropology into a fruitful interdisciplinary mix!
Data Ethnography workshop at this year&amp;rsquo;s Why the World Needs Anthropologists conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange Now Speaks 50 Languages</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/05/orange-now-speaks-50-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 10:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/05/orange-now-speaks-50-languages/</guid>
      <description>In the past couple of weeks we have been working hard on introducing a better language support for the Text add-on. Until recently, Orange supported only a limited number of languages, mostly English and some bigger languages, such as Spanish, German, Arabic, Russian&amp;hellip; Language support was most evident in the list of stopwords, normalization and POS tagging.
Related: Text Workshops in Ljubljana
Stopwords come from NLTK library, so we can only offer whatever is available there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Workshops in Ljubljana</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/09/11/text-workshops-in-ljubljana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 13:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/09/11/text-workshops-in-ljubljana/</guid>
      <description>In the past month, we had two workshops that focused on text mining. The first one, Faksi v praksi, was organized by the University of Ljubljana Career Centers, where high school students learned about what we do at the Faculty of Computer and Information Science. We taught them what text mining is and how to group a collection of documents in Orange. The second one took on a more serious note, as the public sector employees joined us for the third set of workshops from the Ministry of Public Affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis: New Features</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/08/04/text-analysis-new-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 11:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/08/04/text-analysis-new-features/</guid>
      <description>As always, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working hard to bring you new functionalities and improvements. Recently, we&amp;rsquo;ve released Orange version 3.4.5 and Orange3-Text version 0.2.5. We focused on the Text add-on since we are lately holding a lot of text mining workshops. The next one will be at Digital Humanities 2017 in Montreal, QC, Canada in a couple of days and we simply could not resist introducing some sexy new features_._
Related: Text Preprocessing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Preprocessing</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/06/19/text-preprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 08:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/06/19/text-preprocessing/</guid>
      <description>In data mining, preprocessing is key. And in text mining, it is the key and the door. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s the most vital step in the analysis.
Related: Text Mining add-on
So what does preprocessing do? Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at an example. Place Corpus widget from Text add-on on the canvas. Open it and load Grimm-tales-selected. As always, first have a quick glance of the data in Corpus Viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Text Analysis for Social Scientists</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/06/09/workshop-text-analysis-for-social-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 13:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/06/09/workshop-text-analysis-for-social-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was no ordinary day at the Faculty of Computer and Information Science, University of Ljubljana - there was an unusually high proportion of Social Sciences students, researchers and other professionals in our classrooms. It was all because of a Text Analysis for Social Scientists workshop.
Related: Data Mining for Political Scientists
Text mining is becoming a popular method across sciences and it was time to showcase what it (and Orange) can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining for Political Scientists</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/11/30/data-mining-for-political-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 08:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/11/30/data-mining-for-political-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Being a political scientist, I did not even hear about data mining before I&amp;rsquo;ve joined Biolab. And naturally, as with all good things, data mining started to grow on me. Give me some data, connect a bunch of widgets and see the magic happen!
But hold on! There are still many social scientists out there who haven&amp;rsquo;t yet heard about the wonderful world of data mining, text mining and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining: version 0.2.0</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/09/23/text-mining-version-0-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 14:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/09/23/text-mining-version-0-2-0/</guid>
      <description>Orange3-Text has just recently been polished, updated and enhanced! Our GSoC student Alexey has helped us greatly to achieve another milestone in Orange development and release the latest 0.2.0 version of our text mining add-on. The new release, which is already available on PyPi, includes Wikipedia and SimHash widgets and a rehaul of Bag of Words, Topic Modeling and Corpus Viewer.
Wikipedia widget allows retrieving sources from Wikipedia API and can handle multiple queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rehaul of Text Mining Add-On</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/07/05/rehaul-of-text-mining-add-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 06:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/07/05/rehaul-of-text-mining-add-on/</guid>
      <description>Google Summer of Code is progressing nicely and some major improvements are already live! Our students have been working hard and today we&amp;rsquo;re thanking Alexey for his work on Text Mining add-on. Two major tasks before the midterms were to introduce Twitter widget and rehaul Preprocess Text. Twitter widget was designed to be a part of our summer school program and it worked beautifully. We&amp;rsquo;ve introduced youngsters to the world of data mining through social networks and one of the most exciting things was to see whether we can predict the author from the tweet content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>