<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>article on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in article on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 13:28:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 100 Changemakers in Central and Eastern Europe</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/11/18/top-100-changemakers-in-central-and-eastern-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 13:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/11/18/top-100-changemakers-in-central-and-eastern-europe/</guid>
      <description>Recently Orange and one of its inventors, Blaž Zupan, have been recognized as one of the top 100 changemakers in the region. A 2016 New Europe 100 is an annual list of innovators and entrepreneurs in Central and Eastern Europe highlighting novel approaches to pressing problems.
Orange has been recognized for making data more approachable, which has been our goal from the get-go. The tool is continually being developed with the end user in mind - someone who wants to analyze his/her data quickly, visually, interactively, and efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JMLR Publishes Article on Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2013/10/03/jmlr-publishes-article-on-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 02:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013/10/03/jmlr-publishes-article-on-orange/</guid>
      <description>Journal of Machine Learning Research has just published our paper on Orange. In the paper we focus on its Python scripting part. We have last reported on Orange scripting at ECML/PKDD 2004. The manuscript was well received (over 270 citations on Google Scholar), but it is now entirely outdated. This was also our only formal publication on Orange scripting. With publication in JMLR this is now a current description of Orange and will be, for a while :-), Orange’s primary reference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>