<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geo on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/geo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geo on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/geo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining COVID-19 Epidemics: Part 2</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/2020-04-09-covid-19-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/2020-04-09-covid-19-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Previously on Data Mining COVID-19 Epidemics: Part 1: we fired up a COVID-19 epidemics data set and looked at some basic visualizations. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t dirtied your hands with it yet, check that out first.
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll try putting the data on a map. We&amp;rsquo;ll also expand on the &amp;ldquo;data mining is interactive&amp;rdquo; mantra by creating some animations showing the epidemics spread throughout the world.
Prerequisite: installing add-ons Orange already comes with a great selection of widgets that work with all sorts of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange at GIS Ostrava</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/4/24/orange-at-gis-ostrava/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/4/24/orange-at-gis-ostrava/</guid>
      <description>Ostrava is a city in the north-east of the Czech Republic and is the capital of the Moravian-Silesian Region. GIS Ostrava is a yearly conference organized by Jiří Horák and his team at the Technical University of Ostrava. University has a nice campus with a number of new developments. I have learned that this is the largest university campus in central and eastern Europe, as most of the universities, like mine, are city universities with buildings dispersed around the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining and Machine Learning for Economists</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/07/17/data-mining-and-machine-learning-for-economists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 09:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/07/17/data-mining-and-machine-learning-for-economists/</guid>
      <description>Last week Blaž, Marko and I held a week long introductory Data Mining and Machine Learning course at the Ljubljana Doctoral Summer School 2018. We got a room full of dedicated students and we embarked on a journey through standard and advanced machine learning techniques, all presented of course in Orange. We have covered a wide array of topics, from different clustering techniques (hierarchical clustering, k-means) to predictive models (logistic regression, naive Bayes, decision trees, random forests), regression and regularization, projections, text mining and image analytics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>