<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentation on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/documentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentation on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 12:18:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Tips and Tricks for Using Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/10/17/tips-for-using-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 12:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/10/17/tips-for-using-orange/</guid>
      <description>TIP #1: Follow tutorials and example workflows to get started.
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to start using new software. Where does one start, especially a total novice in data mining? For this exact reason we&amp;rsquo;ve prepared Getting Started With Orange - YouTube tutorials for complete beginners. Example workflows on the other hand can be accessed via Help - Examples.
TIP #2: Make use of Orange documentation.
You can access it in three ways:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Widget Documentation</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/09/04/updated-widget-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/09/04/updated-widget-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Happy news for all passionate Orange users! We’ve uploaded documentation for our Orange 3 widget selection.
Right click and select &amp;ldquo;Help&amp;rdquo; or press F1.
 
It’s easy to use. To learn more about a particular wigdet, click on the widget. Either use right click and select “Help” or press F1. A new window will open with a widget description and an example for its use. There are also screenshots included as visual help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New scripting tutorial</title>
      <link>/blog/2013/01/06/new-scripting-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2013/01/06/new-scripting-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Orange just got a new, completely rewritten scripting tutorial. The tutorial uses Orange class hierarchy as introduced for version 2.5. The tutorial is supposed to be a gentle introduction in Orange scripting. It includes many examples, from really simple ones to those more complex. To give you a hint about the later, here is the code for learner with feature subset selection from:
class SmallLearner(Orange.classification.PyLearner): def __init__(self, base_learner=Orange.classification.bayes.NaiveLearner, name=&#39;small&#39;, m=5): self.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>