<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>overfitting on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/overfitting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in overfitting on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 12:26:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/overfitting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Properly Test Models</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/11/29/how-to-properly-test-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 12:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/11/29/how-to-properly-test-models/</guid>
      <description>On Monday we finished the second part of the workshop for the Statistical Office of Republic of Slovenia. The crowd was tough - these guys knew their numbers and asked many challenging questions. And we loved it!
One thing we discussed was how to properly test your model. Ok, we know never to test on the same data you&amp;rsquo;ve built your model with, but even training and testing on separate data is sometimes not enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overfitting and Regularization</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/03/12/overfitting-and-regularization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 16:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/03/12/overfitting-and-regularization/</guid>
      <description>A week ago I used Orange to explain the effects of regularization. This was the second lecture in the Data Mining class, the first one was on linear regression. My introduction to the benefits of regularization used a simple data set with a single input attribute and a continuous class. I drew a data set in Orange, and then used Polynomial Regression widget (from Prototypes add-on) to plot the linear fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A visit from the Tilburg University</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/10/02/a-visit-from-the-tilburg-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 12:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/10/02/a-visit-from-the-tilburg-university/</guid>
      <description>Biolab is currently hosting two amazing data scientists from the Tilburg University - dr. Marie Nilsen and dr. Eric Postma, who are preparing a 20-lecture MOOC on data science for non-technical audience. A part of the course will use Orange. The majority of their students is coming from humanities, law, economy and behavioral studies, thus we are discussing options and opportunities for adapting Orange for social scientists. Another great thing is that the course is designed for beginner level data miners, showcasing that anybody can mine the data and learn from it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>