<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>predictive analytics on Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/predictive-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in predictive analytics on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 12:26:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/predictive-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Properly Test Models</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/11/29/how-to-properly-test-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 12:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/11/29/how-to-properly-test-models/</guid>
      <description>On Monday we finished the second part of the workshop for the Statistical Office of Republic of Slovenia. The crowd was tough - these guys knew their numbers and asked many challenging questions. And we loved it!
One thing we discussed was how to properly test your model. Ok, we know never to test on the same data you&amp;rsquo;ve built your model with, but even training and testing on separate data is sometimes not enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model replaces Classify and Regression</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/07/model-replaces-classify-and-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 14:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/07/model-replaces-classify-and-regression/</guid>
      <description>Did you recently wonder where did Classification Tree go? Or what happened to Majority?
Orange 3.4.0 introduced a new widget category, Model, which now contains all supervised learning algorithms in one place and replaces the separate Classify and Regression categories.
This, however, was not a mere cosmetic change to the widget hierarchy. We wanted to simplify the interface for new users and make finding an appropriate learning algorithm easier. Moreover, now you can reuse some workflows on different data sets, say housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining for Political Scientists</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/11/30/data-mining-for-political-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 08:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/11/30/data-mining-for-political-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Being a political scientist, I did not even hear about data mining before I&amp;rsquo;ve joined Biolab. And naturally, as with all good things, data mining started to grow on me. Give me some data, connect a bunch of widgets and see the magic happen!
But hold on! There are still many social scientists out there who haven&amp;rsquo;t yet heard about the wonderful world of data mining, text mining and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Predictions</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/01/22/predictive-analytics-with-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 16:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/01/22/predictive-analytics-with-orange/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool things about being a data scientist is being able to predict. That is, predict before we know the actual outcome. I am not talking about verifying your favorite classification algorithm here, and I am not talking about cross-validation or classification accuracies or AUC or anything like that. I am talking about the good old prediction. This is where our very own Predictions widget comes to help.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>