<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>orange25 on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/orange25/</link>
    <description>Recent content in orange25 on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/orange25/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The easy way to install add-ons</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/11/30/the-easy-way-to-install-add-ons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/11/30/the-easy-way-to-install-add-ons/</guid>
      <description>The possibility of extending functionality of Orange through add-ons has been present for a long time. In fact, we never provided the toolbox for crunching bioinformatical data as an integral part of Orange; it has always been an add-on. The exact mechanism of distribution of add-ons has changed significantly in the last year to simplify the process for add-on authors and to make it more standards-compliant. Among other things, this enables system administrators to install add-ons system-wide directly from PyPi using easy_install or pip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange 2.5: code conversion</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/12/20/orange-2-5-code-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/12/20/orange-2-5-code-conversion/</guid>
      <description>Orange 2.5 unifies Orange&amp;rsquo;s C++ core and Python modules into a single module hierarchy. To use the new module hierarchy, import Orange instead of orange and accompanying orng* modules. While we will maintain backward compatibility in 2.* releases, we nevertheless suggest programmers to use the new interface. The provided conversion tool can help refactor your code to use the new interface.
The conversion script, orange2to25.py, resides in Orange&amp;rsquo;s main directory. To refactor accuracy8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange 2.5 progress</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/05/20/orange-2-5-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 15:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/05/20/orange-2-5-progress/</guid>
      <description>We decided that we should reorganize Orange to provide more intuitive interface to the scripting interface. The next release, Orange 2.5 is getting better every day. But fear not, dear reader, we are working hard to ensure that your scripts will still work.
In the last morning of the camp in Bohinj we decided to use undercase_separated names instead of CamelCase. We have been steadily converting them and the deprecation utilities by Aleš help a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biolab retreat Februar 2011</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/02/11/biolab-retreat-februar-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 13:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/02/11/biolab-retreat-februar-2011/</guid>
      <description>From Wednesday, 2nd February 2011, to Saturday, 5th February 2011, we have been on working retreat at Lake Bohinj. The whole Bioinformatics Laboratory of the Faculty of Computer and Information technology has temporary moved to a nice house just few meters from the lake, enjoing the nature and without any distractions. Plan: working on the next version of Orange, Orange 2.5 and documentation rewrite. Orange 2.5 will have a better and restructured Python scripting interface along with great and shinny documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>