<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gsoc on Orange</title>
    <link>/categories/gsoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gsoc on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 17:32:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/gsoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of Classification Probabilities</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/16/polynomial-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 17:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/16/polynomial-classification/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest blog from the Google Summer of Code project.
Polynomial Classification widget is implemented as a part of my Google Summer of Code project along with other widgets in educational add-on (see my previous blog). It visualizes probabilities for two-class classification (target vs. rest) using color gradient and contour lines, and it can do so for any Orange learner.
Here is an example workflow. The data comes from the File widget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive k-Means</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/12/interactive-k-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 12:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/12/interactive-k-means/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest blog from the Google Summer of Code project.
As a part of my Google Summer of Code project I started developing educational widgets and assemble them in an Educational Add-On for Orange. Educational widgets can be used by students to understand how some key data mining algorithms work and by teachers to demonstrate the working of these algorithms.
Here I describe an educational widget for interactive k-means clustering, an algorithm that splits the data into clusters by finding cluster centroids such that the distance between data points and their corresponding centroid is minimized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Univariate GSoC Success</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/04/14/univariate-gsoc-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 08:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/04/14/univariate-gsoc-success/</guid>
      <description>Google Summer of Code application period has come to an end. We&amp;rsquo;ve received 34 applications, some of which were of truly high quality. Now it&amp;rsquo;s upon us to select the top performing candidates, but before that we wanted to have an overlook of the candidate pool. We&amp;rsquo;ve gathered data from our Google Form application and gave it a quick view in Orange.
First, we needed to preprocess the data a bit, since it came in a messy form of strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange at Google Summer of Code 2016</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/03/03/orange-at-google-summer-of-code-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 08:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/03/03/orange-at-google-summer-of-code-2016/</guid>
      <description>Orange team is extremely excited to be a part of this year&amp;rsquo;s Google Summer of Code! GSoC is a great opportunity for students around the world to spend their summer contributing to an open-source software, gaining experience and earning money.
Accepted students will help us develop Orange (or other chosen OSS project) from May to August. Each student is expected to select and define a project of his/her interest and will be ascribed a mentor to guide him/her through the entire process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange GSoC: Computer vision add-on for Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/05/15/orange-gsoc-computer-vision-add-on-for-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/05/15/orange-gsoc-computer-vision-add-on-for-orange/</guid>
      <description>This summer I got the chance to develop an add-on for Orange that will introduce basic computer vision functionality, as a part of Google Summer of Code.
The add-on will consist of a set of widgets, each with it&amp;rsquo;s own dedicated purpose, which can be seamlessly connected to provide most commonly used image preprocessing functionality.
Here is a list of the widgets:
 Widget for viewing image files (add description) Widget for resizing an image Widget for rotation/flipping of the image Widget for converting the color mode (RGB, HSV, Grayscale etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange GSoC: A Fully-Featured Neural Network Library Implementation with Extension for Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/05/06/orange-gsoc-a-fully-featured-neural-network-library-implementation-with-extension-for-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 09:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/05/06/orange-gsoc-a-fully-featured-neural-network-library-implementation-with-extension-for-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to build a neural network library based on some great existing NN libraries, notably the Flood Library, which already provides a fully functional Multilayer Perceptron (MLP) implementation. The project starts with implementing a robust, efficient feed forward neural network library, and then will extend it in significant ways that add support for state-of-the-art deep learning techniques. Additional extensions include building a PCA framework and improving existing training algorithms and error functional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange GSoC: Multi-Target Learning for Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/04/30/orange-gsoc-multi-target-learning-for-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/04/30/orange-gsoc-multi-target-learning-for-orange/</guid>
      <description>Orange already supports multi-target classification, but the current implementation of clustering trees is written in Python. One of the five projects Orange has chosen at this year&amp;rsquo;s Google Summer of Code is the implementation of clustering trees in C. The goal of my project is to speed up the building time of clustering trees and lower their spatial complexity, especially when used in random forests. Implementation will be based on Orange&amp;rsquo;s SimpleTreeLearner and will be integrated with Orange 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This year five students participate in Google Summer of Code</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/04/24/this-year-five-students-participate-in-google-summer-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 10:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/04/24/this-year-five-students-participate-in-google-summer-of-code/</guid>
      <description>This year five students have been accepted to participate in Google Summer of Code and contribute to Orange in their summer time. Congratulations!
 Amela – Widgets for statistics Andrej T. – Computer vision add-on for Orange CoderWilliam – A Fully-Featured Neural Network Library Implementation Based On the Flood Library with Extension for Deep Learning Makarov Dmitry – Text mining add-on for Orange Miran Levar – Multi-Target Learning for Orange  Overall, 1,212 students have been accepted this year to various open source organizations from all around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange is again participating in GSoC</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/03/27/orange-is-again-participating-in-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 09:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/03/27/orange-is-again-participating-in-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>This year Orange is again participating in Google Summer of Code as a mentoring organization. Student proposal submission period is running and the deadline is on 6th April. We have prepared a page on our Trac with more information about the Google Summer of Code program, especially how the interested students should apply with their proposals. There is also a list of of some ideas we are proposing for this year but feel free to suggest your own ideas how you could contribute to Orange and make it even better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange 2.5a2 available</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/01/23/orange-2-5a2-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 11:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/01/23/orange-2-5a2-available/</guid>
      <description>Orange 2.5a2 has been uploaded to PyPI. It now includes basic support for multi-label classification (developed during the Google Summer of Code 2011), some new widget icons and documentation for basket format. Release is also tagged on our Bitbucket repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-label classification (and Multi-target prediction) in Orange</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/01/09/multi-label-classification-and-multi-target-prediction-in-orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2012/01/09/multi-label-classification-and-multi-target-prediction-in-orange/</guid>
      <description>The last summer, student Wencan Luo participated in Google Summer of Code to implement Multi-label Classification in Orange. He provided a framework, implemented a few algorithms and some prototype widgets. His work has been &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo; in our repositories for too long; finally, we have merged part of his code into Orange (widgets are not there yet &amp;hellip;) and added a more general support for multi-target prediction.
You can load multi-label tab-delimited data (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Mentor Summit</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/10/26/gsoc-mentor-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/10/26/gsoc-mentor-summit/</guid>
      <description>On 22th and 23th October 2011 there was Google Summer of Code Mentor Summit in Mountain View, California. Google Summer of Code is Google&amp;rsquo;s program for encouraging students to work on open-source projects during their summer break. Because this year Orange participated in this program too, we decided to participate also in this summit and get to know other mentors, other open-source projects and organizations, exchange our experiences, learn something new, and improve our connections and collaborations with others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Review: Visualizations with Qt</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/09/03/gsoc-review-visualizations-with-qt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 08:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/09/03/gsoc-review-visualizations-with-qt/</guid>
      <description>During the course of this summer, I created a new plotting library for Orange plot, replacing the use of PyQwt. I can say that I have succesfully completed my project, but the library (and especially the visualization widgets) could still use some more work. The new library supports a similar interface, so little change is needed to convert individual widgets, but it also has several advantages over the old implementation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Review: Multi-label Classification Implementation</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/09/02/gsoc-review-multi-label-classification-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 05:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/09/02/gsoc-review-multi-label-classification-implementation/</guid>
      <description>Traditional single-label classification is concerned with learning from a set of examples that are associated with a single label l from a set of disjoint labels L, |L| &amp;gt; 1. If |L| = 2, then the learning problem is called a binary classification problem, while if |L| &amp;gt; 2, then it is called a multi-class classification problem (Tsoumakas &amp;amp; Katakis, 2007).
Multi-label classification methods are increasingly used by many applications, such as textual data classification, protein function classification, music categorization and semantic scene classification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Review: MF - Matrix Factorization Techniques for Data Mining</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/09/01/gsoc-review-mf-matrix-factorization-techniques-for-data-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/09/01/gsoc-review-mf-matrix-factorization-techniques-for-data-mining/</guid>
      <description>MF - Matrix Factorization Techniques for Data Mining is a Python scripting library which includes a number of published matrix factorization algorithms, initialization methods, quality and performance measures and facilitates the combination of these to produce new strategies. The library represents a unified and efficient interface to matrix factorization algorithms and methods.
The MF works with numpy dense matrices and scipy sparse matrices (where this is possible to save on space).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange GSoC: Multi-label Classification Implementation</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/07/20/orange-gsoc-multi-label-classification-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 11:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/07/20/orange-gsoc-multi-label-classification-implementation/</guid>
      <description>Multi-label classification is one of the three projects of Google Summer Code 2011 for Orange. The main goal is to extend the Orange to support multi-label, including dataset support, two basic multi-label classifications-problem-transformation methods &amp;amp; algorithm adaptation methods, evaluation measures, GUI support, documentation, testing, and so on.
My name is Wencan Luo, from China. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to work with my mentor Matija. Until now, we have finished a framework for multi-label support for Orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange GSoC: Visualizations with Qt</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/06/30/orange-gsoc-visualizations-with-qt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/06/30/orange-gsoc-visualizations-with-qt/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Miha Čančula and this summer I&amp;rsquo;m working on Orange as part of Google&amp;rsquo;s Summer of Code program, mentored by Miha Štajdohar. My task is to replace the current visualization framework based on Qwt with a custom library, depending only on Qt. This library will better support Orange&amp;rsquo;s very specific visualizations and will replace the unmaintained PyQwt.
I have a lot of experience with Qt and its graphics classes, both in C++ and Python, but I&amp;rsquo;m relatively now to Orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange GSoC: MF Techniques for Data Mining</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/06/24/orange-gsoc-mf-techniques-for-data-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/06/24/orange-gsoc-mf-techniques-for-data-mining/</guid>
      <description>I am one of three students who are working on GSoC projects for Orange this year. The objective of the project Matrix Factorization Techniques for Data Mining is to provide the Orange community with a unified and efficient interface to matrix factorization algorithms and methods.
For that purpose I have been developing a library which will include a number of published factorization algorithms and initialization methods and will facilitate combinations of these to produce new strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted GSoC 2011 students announced</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/04/25/accepted-gsoc-2011-students-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 08:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/04/25/accepted-gsoc-2011-students-announced/</guid>
      <description>Accepted proposals/projects for Google Summer of Code 2011 have been announced. We got 3 students which will this year work on Orange:
  Marinka Žitnik: Matrix Factorization Techniques for Data Mining
  Miha Čančula: 2D visualization using PyQt
  Wencan Luo: Multi-label classification
  Congrats to all accepted students. We are looking forward working with you. And for all other students: please apply again next year. Your proposals were good, but we just could not accept everybody.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student application period for GSoC 2011 has ended</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/04/08/student-application-period-for-gsoc-2011-has-ended/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 07:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/04/08/student-application-period-for-gsoc-2011-has-ended/</guid>
      <description>Student application period for Google Summer of Code 2011 has ended. We got 47 proposals from students all around the world. Now it is time for us to evaluate them and select the best proposals and the best students to work this year on Orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our GSoC 2011 posters</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/03/29/our-gsoc-2011-posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 10:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/03/29/our-gsoc-2011-posters/</guid>
      <description>We have made our own recruitment posters for this year&amp;rsquo;s Google Summer of Code inviting students to participate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange has been accepted into GSoC 2011</title>
      <link>/blog/2011/03/18/orange-has-been-accepted-into-gsoc-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2011/03/18/orange-has-been-accepted-into-gsoc-2011/</guid>
      <description>This year Orange has been accepted into the Google summer of Code program as a mentoring organization. It is one of 175 open-source organizations/projects/groups which will this year mentor students while they will be working on those accepted open source projects.
We have prepared a page on our Trac with more information about the Google Summer of Code program, especially how the interested students should apply with their proposals. There is also a list of of some ideas we are proposing for this year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>