<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tides Foundation on Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/Tides-Foundation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tides Foundation on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/Tides-Foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to grow trees in a marmalade factory?</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-06-01-blog-minions-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-06-01-blog-minions-new/</guid>
      <description>What if we told you that it is possible to teach data mining to kids in elementary school in an enjoyable way? You’d say,
&amp;ldquo;Impossible!&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s too much to ask of a kid!&amp;rdquo;.
We say, &amp;ldquo;Just watch; it can be done in a fun and informative way that will help these kids learn fundamental logical thinking patterns!&amp;rdquo;
A week before our Tuesday visit, the kids from Alojzij Šuštar elementary school in Ljubljana took a trip to the Ljubljana Zoo, paying close attention to animals and their features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have launched a new project on the topic of AI in schools</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-05-12-Google-Tides/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-05-12-Google-Tides/</guid>
      <description>We have successfully launched a new project about AI and data science in elementary and high schools.
AI is the technology of the century, yet too few kids and education professionals know about its concepts, ideas and applications. The project, funded by Google.org and Tides Foundation, is aimed at bringing AI to teachers and kids by designing hands-on workshops by focusing on conceptual learning and applications.
During the course of the project, between January 31st 2022 and July 31st 2023, we expect to carry out several activities whose long term outcome is expected to improve overall education about AI in Slovenia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
