<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orange</title>
    <link>/blog/Orange/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Orange</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/Orange/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Orange Webinar for Educators #1: Where to Start?</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-04-26-edu-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-04-26-edu-webinar/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, May 26, 2022, at 16:00 CET, we will organize a webinar for educators who either use or are interested in using Orange Data Mining in data science training.
The webinar will feature a short demo on using Orange for training in machine learning. We will showcase several data visualization and exploration widgets and show you some tricks that you could use in your training sessions. We will also present our GitHub repository with our openly-available Orange training material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training with Orange: A Tutorial at AIME 2022 in Halifax</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-04-26-amia-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-04-26-amia-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>When June 14, 2022
Where Halifax, Canada. This is a half-day, on site tutorial organized during the AIME 2022 conference.
On Tutorial In the tutorial, we will claim and demonstrate that, given the right tool, it may take only a few hours to familiarize outsiders in data science.
The tutorial is intended for teachers and trainees: we will present both the training steps and, as a demonstration, go through the actual training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing the photographs collection with the help of machine learning</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-02-11-edit-image-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-02-11-edit-image-collection/</guid>
      <description>The core element of Orange&amp;rsquo;s image analysis is embedding images in the vector space. Last year, we upgraded the embedding server infrastructure, enabling around ten times faster image embedding.
We switched from an old cluster with a fixed number of workers for each embedding to a new infrastructure where workers turn on when needed. It means that when a user sends images to the embedder, it will turn on as many instances as required until processors&#39; cores are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Jargon</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-02-01-machine-learning-jargon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-02-01-machine-learning-jargon/</guid>
      <description>We all know each profession has its own jargon. Most of us remember from any hospital series something like: &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Pass me the scalpel, stat!&amp;rdquo; Meaning &amp;ldquo;give me the scalpel quickly&amp;rdquo;.
Data scientists are no different. We have our own terminology that requires some getting used to. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of common terms that we use in machine learning. Some terms are specific to Orange and might not be used elsewhere. The post is intended to get you familiar with concepts used in Orange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange in Classroom, pt. 2</title>
      <link>/blog/2022/2022-01-14-universities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022/2022-01-14-universities/</guid>
      <description>A year ago, we put out a survey asking the Orange community if they use Orange for teaching (or learning) and at which educational institution. We got around 300 replies from 200 universities in the first round.
In the past year, we were starting to establish a global community of educators that teach statistics, data mining, and machine learning (or perhaps something entirely different) and are using Orange for this purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange in Classroom</title>
      <link>/blog/2021/2021-01-11-orange-in-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021/2021-01-11-orange-in-classroom/</guid>
      <description>Orange in Classroom About three weeks ago, we put out a short survey asking professors, teaching assistants, and students to tell us how they use Orange in class. We have gotten four-hundred responses, and it turns out that over two hundred universities from around the world actively use Orange in the classroom.
We sincerely thank everyone for the answers!
 Here is a a list of universities, in alphabetical order, we have compiled from the survey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
